<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Himss on News</title>
    <link>/categories/himss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Himss on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 15:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/himss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Will HIMSS 18 Mourn the Passing of the Traditional Office Visit?</title>
      <link>/2018/03/13/will-himss-18-mourn-the-passing-of-the-traditional-office-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/13/will-himss-18-mourn-the-passing-of-the-traditional-office-visit/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare is evolving quickly and HIMSS 18 offers a broad range of healthcare issues to explore, but will it mourn the passing of the traditional office visit and embrace new HIT driven meet ups?
New requirements for implementing HIT systems are changing as new health IT priorities and procedures emerge. Convergence in the health care sector is accelerating the need for interoperability, not just for EHRs, but also across clinical, financial, and operational systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Dental Digital Health Technology More Advanced Than Other Healthcare Specialties?</title>
      <link>/2018/03/29/why-is-dental-digital-health-technology-more-advanced-than-other-healthcare-specialties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 19:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/29/why-is-dental-digital-health-technology-more-advanced-than-other-healthcare-specialties/</guid>
      <description>Technology has helped achieve unimaginable feats in the field of health and medicine. Hi-tech equipment and cutting-edge techniques are helping doctors and healthcare specialists make stunning medical breakthroughs every day. While these advancements are being observed in all perspectives of healthcare, its highest benefactor seems to be the dental department.
Dentistry has developed like no other area of medicine in the last decade. If you wake up in the middle of the night with a sensitive tooth problem, the issue can be permanently resolved during the (same) day That kind of superfast prognosis and diagnosis is, however, either non-existent or extremely rare for other problematic diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>