<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare It on News</title>
    <link>/categories/healthcare-it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare It on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 01:35:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/healthcare-it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Features of EHR Software From the Perspective of a Healthcare Worker and Current Patient | The Healthcare Guys</title>
      <link>/2018/08/31/important-features-of-ehr-software-from-the-perspective-of-a-healthcare-worker-and-current-patient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 01:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/31/important-features-of-ehr-software-from-the-perspective-of-a-healthcare-worker-and-current-patient/</guid>
      <description>Current State of Healthcare IT Health Information Technology (HIT) is huge in the healthcare industry. Times are changing and so are the ways we record patient data. Nowadays, it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to be at the doctor&amp;rsquo;s office spending at least 10 minutes going through questions you most likely have gone over and over before. Scenarios where one doctor is not enough, and you find yourself in a new place, the repetition of answering the same questions becomes tiresome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Health Tech Companies Need To Know Their Customers</title>
      <link>/2018/08/15/why-health-tech-companies-need-to-know-their-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 19:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/15/why-health-tech-companies-need-to-know-their-customers/</guid>
      <description>In an era jam packed with new technology and brilliant people on a mission to save lives, it’s no wonder health tech, digital health, mobile health, and telehealth companies are on the rise.
Now more than ever, physicians and medical teams have access to powerful tools that improve how they care for patients. And patients have access to technology they can use at home that can give them more treatment options and, in many cases, can even save their lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMS’s Proposed PI Rule Changes is a Good Start, But Does it Address Enough?</title>
      <link>/2018/05/28/cmss-proposed-pi-rule-changes-is-a-good-start-but-does-it-address-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 01:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/28/cmss-proposed-pi-rule-changes-is-a-good-start-but-does-it-address-enough/</guid>
      <description>Federal healthcare organizations such as CMS have spent billions of dollars over the years trying to bridge the gap between medical data and quality patient care with interoperability requirements and data integration, the mesh used to try and bridge the gap. Many government rules have been written to address the type of mesh needed and many EHR companies have claimed to meet these government requirements and claim the throne of the ultimate mesh maker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hordenine: Your Companion in Weight Loss and Some Weight Management Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/04/30/hordenine-your-companion-in-weight-loss-and-some-weight-management-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 22:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/30/hordenine-your-companion-in-weight-loss-and-some-weight-management-apps/</guid>
      <description>Are you someone who has never been able to reach your body weight goals? Well, you are not alone. There are millions of people who are unable to shed off those extra pounds off their body, no matter how much they try.
According to a 2017 study, published in Time, obesity now leads to more early preventable deaths in the US than smoking. This has fuelled the growth of the global weight-loss industry, including meal plans, diet pills and gym memberships, which has reached a value of $66.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How 3D Printing Has Transformed the Medical Sector</title>
      <link>/2018/04/28/how-3d-printing-has-transformed-the-medical-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 21:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/28/how-3d-printing-has-transformed-the-medical-sector/</guid>
      <description>3D printing has become the most sort out technology in the world currently. This has led to applications in different sectors of the economy. Due to its vast applications, 3D printing has transformed many lives in different ways. Is 3D printing applicable in the medical sector? Yes, currently the medical sector has embraced this technology in various ways. Also known as, ‘Rapid Prototyping’ 3D printing has enabled the creation of new objects similar to existing objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare IT Trends to Watch Through 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/03/15/healthcare-it-trends-to-watch-through-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 15:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/15/healthcare-it-trends-to-watch-through-2018/</guid>
      <description>Technological innovations and developments in IT are transforming the healthcare industry at every level. From fostering better relationships between patient and caregiver, to facilitating improved and more valuable data analysis, the potential rewards offered by modern technology for all stakeholders is significant. Here are three examples of areas of technology that are changing the face of healthcare for the better.
Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Artificial intelligence, which can be defined simply as the simulation of human intelligence processes (such as learning and reasoning) by computer systems, has been disrupting other industries for several years, with tech, telecoms, and financial services leading the charge in this space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Benefits of Social Media in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/03/13/5-benefits-of-social-media-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/13/5-benefits-of-social-media-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Technology, media and the internet has been having a huge impact in our lives since a long time now. But the sudden rise in social media usage has brought in much better and more advanced opportunities to business, marketing and general public awareness. The popularity of social media continues to increase and demographics show that the most growing users of social media are individuals aged 45-54.
Gone are the days when healthcare could only be provided through a practitioner by seeing them face-to-face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Features That Patients Want From a Medical Website</title>
      <link>/2018/02/07/3-features-that-patients-want-from-a-medical-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 23:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/07/3-features-that-patients-want-from-a-medical-website/</guid>
      <description>The way your website looks makes a lasting first impression. It creates a digital handshake – that initial introduction and “hello” to your patients. Working with our proprietary four-step process, at iHealthSpot, we launch new medical website designs that search engines love and look good no matter what device you are using to look at it; whether it be a laptop, tablet or smartphone. Moreover, we design your site with your viewers in mind, making it easy to navigate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment for Heroin Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>There is a major crisis affecting the health and welfare of many Americans today, and this threat to the state of America’s health isn’t a virus. The threat is the epidemic of heroin use that is affecting people at every level of society in the United States. The current heroin epidemic is larger and more broad-ranging than any addiction crisis we’ve ever seen before, which is why the crisis had gotten the attention of the government and our medical treatment system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Clinical Trial Technology Innovations to Watch For in 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/01/27/5-clinical-trial-technology-innovations-watch-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 20:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/27/5-clinical-trial-technology-innovations-watch-2018/</guid>
      <description>Clinical trial technology has come a long way from when site administrators used a touch-tone keypad on a phone to randomize patients and order drugs. But with so many new features, it’s more challenging than ever for hospital decision makers to choose the right technology for clinical trials running at their facilities. Here, we’ll share key information on what’s changing, to help with these decisions. When making purchasing decisions for the next year, be on the lookout for these helpful new features that will become increasingly essential to clinical trial technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>