<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 01:35:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Features of EHR Software From the Perspective of a Healthcare Worker and Current Patient | The Healthcare Guys</title>
      <link>/2018/08/31/important-features-of-ehr-software-from-the-perspective-of-a-healthcare-worker-and-current-patient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 01:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/31/important-features-of-ehr-software-from-the-perspective-of-a-healthcare-worker-and-current-patient/</guid>
      <description>Current State of Healthcare IT Health Information Technology (HIT) is huge in the healthcare industry. Times are changing and so are the ways we record patient data. Nowadays, it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to be at the doctor&amp;rsquo;s office spending at least 10 minutes going through questions you most likely have gone over and over before. Scenarios where one doctor is not enough, and you find yourself in a new place, the repetition of answering the same questions becomes tiresome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI For Healthcare? Great But Let&#39;s Get These Things Right</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/answered-top-10-snoring-faqs-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/answered-top-10-snoring-faqs-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Whether you are IBM Watson or some other AI system, you seek to find answers to questions that humans can&amp;rsquo;t answer quickly or analytically.
 What&amp;rsquo;s the likelihood of this autoimmune disease in that patient? What does the latest evidence say about this treatment protocol for that cancer? From which zip codes will the next generation of asthma patients come from?  When we ask such cognitive (thinking) questions, there&amp;rsquo;s a big underlying assumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Emerging Tech Can Help Standardize Medical Reporting</title>
      <link>/posts/how-emerging-tech-can-help-standardize-medical-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 22:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-emerging-tech-can-help-standardize-medical-reporting/</guid>
      <description>Medical reporting is an integral part of the medical industry, but a lack of standardized reporting techniques makes the field more complicated than it needs to be. In addition to making it more difficult to care for patients, this has caused the healthcare field to lag behind many other areas that use similar technology. Networked medical systems have their share of risks — any networked system can be susceptible to hacking if the hardware or software isn&amp;rsquo;t upgraded and secured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices to Secure Patient Data</title>
      <link>/2018/08/29/best-practices-to-secure-patient-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 04:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/29/best-practices-to-secure-patient-data/</guid>
      <description>It’s important for healthcare providers to ensure patient data privacy in order to build lasting and meaningful relationship with their customers. However, it’s not easy to secure health data with the growing concerns in cybersecurity threats today.
According to healthcare data breach statistics from 2009 to 2017, 2,181 healthcare data breaches was recorded resulting to theft and exposure of 176,709,305 healthcare records.
There are different ways on how cyber criminals obtain patient data, it could be in the form of hacking, improper disposal of data, theft, unauthorized access/disclosure and other types of breaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mHealth Applications: Brand New Way to Manage Your Healthcare Business</title>
      <link>/posts/mhealth-applications-brand-new-way-to-manage-your-healthcare-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 03:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mhealth-applications-brand-new-way-to-manage-your-healthcare-business/</guid>
      <description>No matter what task you want to complete – make an appointment to have a haircut, buy a pair of trousers or find your way around a new city – there’s probably an app for that. Healthcare industry had no other choice but try to adapt to the mobile revolution: by 2023, the global mHealth market is expected to top $ 102 billion (up from $ 28.32 billion in 2018). Why do both patients and healthcare professionals use mobile applications?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Advancements That Dentists in Arlington Virginia Can Use</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-advancements-that-dentists-in-arlington-virginia-can-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 03:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-advancements-that-dentists-in-arlington-virginia-can-use/</guid>
      <description>Technology has made lives easier for everyone. Today, there are tools, software, and applications which can help people accomplish their tasks faster and easier. Regardless if you’re working in a bank, taking care of your kids at home or attending school regularly, technology will always intervene and provide solutions so you can better fulfill your responsibility. The same is also true when it comes to dentistry. There are several technology advancements which dentists should use in order to satisfy their customers’ needs and wants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Tips to Prepare For Contract Modeling</title>
      <link>/2018/08/28/3-tips-to-prepare-for-contract-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 02:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/28/3-tips-to-prepare-for-contract-modeling/</guid>
      <description>For healthcare organizations struggling to maintain consistent revenue integrity within their revenue cycle, effective contract modeling may be the best long-term solution. Not only does contract modeling allow providers to evaluate the performance of their current payer contracts, but, more importantly, it allows providers to develop a payer strategy that helps drive those payer contracts to deliver more predictable results and reimbursement. But there’s a catch… The data behind the contracts must be accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Family Roles in Addiction Recovery, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/the-importance-of-family-roles-in-addiction-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 12:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-importance-of-family-roles-in-addiction-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Addiction is an issue which affects the whole community. Because even if you’re not addicted to drugs, you’re affected in a way as a family member of a relative. That’s why when a member is drug addict, its effects are reflected in the whole family system, as each member tries to cope with the instability and strange behaviors. While some families may deny the reality to cope with situation, others face the situation head-on and try to understand their role in addiction recovery, hence bringing the household in complete sobriety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/posts/machine-learning-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 04:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/machine-learning-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Information that’s accessible regarding patients is increasing by the day. And we have access to a lot of this data at our fingerprints thanks to advances in technology. We should be able to draw insights from this and put data to work. The first challenge is the huge amount of data that cannot be processed by mere mortals. Machine learning when combined with data can help us make better decisions, transform healthcare, save lives and improve the quality of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral Addictions: Could You Suffer From One of These Compulsive Habits? And Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/08/21/behavioral-addictions-could-you-suffer-from-one-of-these-compulsive-habits-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 01:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/21/behavioral-addictions-could-you-suffer-from-one-of-these-compulsive-habits-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>The topic of addiction commonly draws a person’s attention to things like drugs and alcohol. Though substance abuse continues to be one of the largest forms of addiction in the nation, vodka, tequila, marijuana, heroin, and opiates (to name a few) aren’t the only things a person can indulge in compulsively. Believe it or not, people can also have addictive behaviors. They feel a strong urge or desire to engage in activities despite their negative consequences on themselves, loved ones, career, or the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Savvy Ways to Pass the MCAT</title>
      <link>/posts/tech-savvy-ways-to-pass-the-mcat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tech-savvy-ways-to-pass-the-mcat/</guid>
      <description>Prospective medical students are required to complete the Medical College Admissions Test before starting their medical program. The exam tests the student’s medical knowledge and determines if they are the best fit for the college-based program. Future doctors who hope to start their program soon should review tech-savvy options that enable them to pass the MCAT.
Online Calendars and Apps An online calendar or app is ideal for tracking the information the student covers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRM Can Do More for Both Patients and Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/08/15/crm-can-do-more-for-both-patients-and-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 20:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/15/crm-can-do-more-for-both-patients-and-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Customer relationship management platforms (eg. Salesforce, Hubspot, Base, etc.) have begun to revolutionize the way healthcare system administrators approach patient acquisition, engagement, and retention.
Now that more robust EMRs integrate with the CRM, administrators and physicians are suddenly capable of possessing a comprehensive, 360-degree view of the patient’s journey, from the first phone call, to diagnosis, to treatment, to follow-up, to long-term care, to the last check-in. They can simultaneously track contact preferences, phone calls, emails, payments, everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Health Tech Companies Need To Know Their Customers</title>
      <link>/2018/08/15/why-health-tech-companies-need-to-know-their-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 19:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/15/why-health-tech-companies-need-to-know-their-customers/</guid>
      <description>In an era jam packed with new technology and brilliant people on a mission to save lives, it’s no wonder health tech, digital health, mobile health, and telehealth companies are on the rise.
Now more than ever, physicians and medical teams have access to powerful tools that improve how they care for patients. And patients have access to technology they can use at home that can give them more treatment options and, in many cases, can even save their lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Technology is Changing the Medical and Healthcare Fields?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-technology-is-changing-the-medical-and-healthcare-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 18:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-technology-is-changing-the-medical-and-healthcare-fields/</guid>
      <description>Technology has proven to be the driving force and catalyst for innovation in a variety of different fields. One of those fields in which it has had a major impact on is the healthcare and medical fields. These fields have been around for as long as any of us can remember, but there is no denying the huge changes that technology has led to. The healthcare field in the modern day looks vastly different compared to what it used to, even only a few short decades ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Doctors Use Technology to Treat More Patients</title>
      <link>/posts/how-doctors-use-technology-to-treat-more-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 17:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-doctors-use-technology-to-treat-more-patients/</guid>
      <description>The mandated implementation of electronic health records systems - EHRs for short - has drastically changed the way doctors manage their practices. The inherent efficiencies of digitally tracking patients have led to the ability for doctors to see more patients in a given amount of time. Furthermore, it lets them forgo many of the formalities and redundancies associated with traditional medical care in exchange for a “hit the ground running” approach to patient care and outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Analytics for a Healthcare System</title>
      <link>/posts/the-importance-of-analytics-for-a-healthcare-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 01:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-importance-of-analytics-for-a-healthcare-system/</guid>
      <description>Ever increasing computational power, advances in artificial intelligence, and the lower of the cost computation (because of cloud computing service such as Azure and Amazon Web Services) has enabled healthcare systems – often laggards in quality improvement and technology adoption – to rapidly implement analytics systems. Such systems enable enterprises to analyze and model their processes, engage in meaningful quality and process improvement activities, and prepare to succeed in value and risk-based payment models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AI Will Affect Ophthalmology: Will Your Ophthalmologist Be a Robotic AI?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-ai-will-affect-ophthalmology-will-your-ophthalmologist-be-a-robotic-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 22:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-ai-will-affect-ophthalmology-will-your-ophthalmologist-be-a-robotic-ai/</guid>
      <description>The use of machine learning and AI is growing at a rapid rate in the healthcare sector, being able to tackle tasks many thought wouldn’t be possible just yet. Google researchers are doing just that by teaching a AI algorithm to detect common forms of blindness, specifically diabetic retinopathy—which affects almost a third of diabetes patients, as effectively as real-life trained ophthalmologist. What is diabetic retinopathy? Diabetic retinopathy is a diabetes related complication that affects the eyes, caused by damage to the blood vessels of the light-sensitive tissue at the back of the eye (retina).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Mobile Technology is Helping Developing Countries Gain Access to Better Healthcare</title>
      <link>/posts/how-mobile-technology-is-helping-developing-countries-gain-access-to-better-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 21:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-mobile-technology-is-helping-developing-countries-gain-access-to-better-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>The battle to bring reliable healthcare to the developing parts of the world is still very much an unfinished one. But now, thanks to modern, mobile-focused technologies, the industrializing world has new, promising tools at its disposal for addressing the coverage gap that exists between nations and sometimes between territories within nations. The Problem Being Tackled To begin with, there are two numbers to keep in mind. Rather, two ratios:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These New Medicare Cards Could Help Reduce Fraud</title>
      <link>/posts/these-new-medicare-cards-could-help-reduce-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 19:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/these-new-medicare-cards-could-help-reduce-fraud/</guid>
      <description>The healthcare industry and, specifically, Medicare, is a boon for fraudsters, scammers and would-be identity thieves from all around the world. One primary reason for this trend is the age of Medicare enrollees. With the eligibility age typically set at 65, the elderly are often targeted by — and fall victim to — the scams and tricks perpetrated by others. But Medicare patients have a valuable asset on their side: the Medicare industry itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Device which is Revolutionising Treatment of Spinal Cord Injuries</title>
      <link>/posts/the-device-which-is-revolutionising-treatment-of-spinal-cord-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 19:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-device-which-is-revolutionising-treatment-of-spinal-cord-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Sustaining a spinal cord injury is undoubtedly a traumatic experience, an experience which is universally and tremendously feared. When one thinks of a spinal cord injury, often they will immediately envision an individual whose mobility is severely restricted as a result and is now dependent on a wheelchair for the remainder of their life. However, the prognosis depends on the severity of the injury. Individuals may only suffer mild symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to Check for When Joining a Health Network</title>
      <link>/2018/08/11/what-to-check-for-when-joining-a-health-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 18:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/11/what-to-check-for-when-joining-a-health-network/</guid>
      <description>Do you know what critical information to check for when joining a health network? It can be overwhelming when trying to take in a lot of information at once that will undoubtedly affect your family’s access to quality health care providers when you need those services the most.
Deductibles, Premiums and Policy Accessibility If you are healthy, you might not consider a health network important until you need medical services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient, Compelling Communication With Baby Boomers is All About Choice</title>
      <link>/2018/08/05/efficient-compelling-communication-with-baby-boomers-is-all-about-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/05/efficient-compelling-communication-with-baby-boomers-is-all-about-choice/</guid>
      <description>Professional communication, especially about sensitive financial matters, requires planning, positioning, and analysis. Those best at building positive relationships understand how both they and the person with whom they’re speaking process information. Credibility, honesty, and empathy all matter. And when one tries to compel another into action, setting expectations and customizing the approach according to the audience can raise chances of success significantly. There are many ways to make decisions about tailoring your message and delivery, but a good framework with which to start is the different communication preferences between generations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will HIMSS 18 Mourn the Passing of the Traditional Office Visit?</title>
      <link>/2018/03/13/will-himss-18-mourn-the-passing-of-the-traditional-office-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/13/will-himss-18-mourn-the-passing-of-the-traditional-office-visit/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare is evolving quickly and HIMSS 18 offers a broad range of healthcare issues to explore, but will it mourn the passing of the traditional office visit and embrace new HIT driven meet ups?
New requirements for implementing HIT systems are changing as new health IT priorities and procedures emerge. Convergence in the health care sector is accelerating the need for interoperability, not just for EHRs, but also across clinical, financial, and operational systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Brian Donovan of SE Healthcare Talks About the Value of The Reimbursement Effectiveness Platform to Healthcare Providers</title>
      <link>/2018/08/05/interview-brian-donovan-of-se-healthcare-talks-about-the-value-of-the-reimbursement-effectiveness-platform-to-healthcare-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 01:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/05/interview-brian-donovan-of-se-healthcare-talks-about-the-value-of-the-reimbursement-effectiveness-platform-to-healthcare-providers/</guid>
      <description>SE Healthcare has announced the official rollout of its software platform that would help practices increase revenue through enhanced reimbursement. For this exciting news, we decided to interview Brian Donovan, VP of Business Development at SE Healthcare.
 SE Healthcare has added a new component to the company’s Physician Empowerment Suite, namely, the Reimbursement Effectiveness Platform. Can you tell us more about this platform?
The Reimbursement Effectiveness Platform (RE) is a component of the Physician Empowerment Suite™ (PES).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Genetic Health Testing Company Launches in UK</title>
      <link>/posts/new-genetic-health-testing-company-launches-in-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-genetic-health-testing-company-launches-in-uk/</guid>
      <description>A new genetic health testing company that focuses on preventing life altering medical conditions before they are apparent rather than reacting to them has launched in the UK. Qlu Health offers cancer, cardiac, nutrition and gut testing. Launched by Shamshad Ahmed, founder of Smart Cells International LTD, the UK’s first private stem cell banking company, Qlu Health works with several leading laboratories and researchers around the world to provide a comprehensive and thorough genetic testing health report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 Tips For Financing Your Dental Work</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/top-4-tips-for-financing-your-dental-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 02:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/top-4-tips-for-financing-your-dental-work/</guid>
      <description>Your teeth could use some work, but there’s no money to cover the cost. Choosing the right approach to dental financing is not as difficult as you may think. Use these four tips and it won’t take long to find a plan that’s just right for your budget.
Identify All the Plans That Your Dentist Accepts
You already know that most dentists are happy to share information about all forms of dental insurance they accept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy DOS and DONTS of Marketing Your Business</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/easy-dos-and-donts-of-marketing-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 02:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/easy-dos-and-donts-of-marketing-your-business/</guid>
      <description>You’ve finally started your company.. But now what! When it comes to getting the word out to your customers, marketing your startup is your first priority! If you don’t have a platform, you don’t really have any existing customers. It does take a lot of time to get some traction going which is why 90% of startup companies fail. The biggest reason is that they are making major mistakes when it comes to strategizing and how they use the current marketing content that we have available to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answered! Top 10 Snoring FAQs and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/answered-top-10-snoring-faqs-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 01:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/answered-top-10-snoring-faqs-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been woken by a snorer in the family? You would have noticed them making a harsh buzzing sound with their mouth wide open. To your annoyance, you are wide awake, and the snorer is oblivious. He has no idea he has woken you up. Ever wondered why people snore? Snoring is caused by obstructed breathing, which happens when relaxed throat tissues block the airway in the snorer’s mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What You Need to Know About Medical Device Hacking</title>
      <link>/2018/07/31/what-you-need-to-know-about-medical-device-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 02:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/31/what-you-need-to-know-about-medical-device-hacking/</guid>
      <description>Medical devices are getting more connected every year. From pacemakers to blood sugar monitoring glucometers, these devices now have built-in Wi-Fi connectivity.
That makes it easier for patients and medical professionals to monitor a patient&amp;rsquo;s well-being, but as with any networked system, it is also vulnerable to hacking. What do patients really need to know about medical device hacking?
An Invisible Problem
It can be difficult to tell whether hackers have attacked a device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginner’s Guide to Proteomics and its Importance, Benefits and Uses</title>
      <link>/2018/07/29/beginners-guide-to-proteomics-and-its-importance-benefits-and-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 01:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/29/beginners-guide-to-proteomics-and-its-importance-benefits-and-uses/</guid>
      <description>What is Proteomics?
Defining Proteomics we can say that it is the most efficient study of proteins of different organisms and cells on a large scale basis. The growth in this field is much more rapid and faster than the other digital healthcare techniques and molecular biology. Describing Proteomics much more clearly we can say that it is the analysis or experiment of the proteins on a high approach or systematic way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Things You Need to Know About Fighting Heart Disease in 2018 and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/07/28/3-things-you-need-to-know-about-fighting-heart-disease-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 23:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/28/3-things-you-need-to-know-about-fighting-heart-disease-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Heart disease is one of the leading causes of death among the affluent populations of Western nations. As a result, it should be one of your priorities on the list of diseases you want to prevent. Just because it is common doesn’t mean you have to be a casualty too. There are plenty of ways to fight this and other chronic diseases in 2018, such as the solutions I had the chance to read at https://medtruth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Great Reasons to Choose Home Care for Your Loved Ones</title>
      <link>/2018/07/27/5-great-reasons-to-choose-home-care-for-your-loved-ones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 02:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/27/5-great-reasons-to-choose-home-care-for-your-loved-ones/</guid>
      <description>When the time comes for one or both of your parents to start looking for full time care, what are the options? Well, these days, home care is right up there with the best and, here in Montreal, it is certainly worth looking into. Private home care offers a myriad of services that always place the patient’s needs at the top of the tree. If you are thinking seriously about home care assistance for your loved ones, please read this article first for some valuable information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor on the Brink of a Burnout? Warning Signs That You Need Help</title>
      <link>/2018/07/27/doctor-on-the-brink-of-a-burnout-warning-signs-that-you-need-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/27/doctor-on-the-brink-of-a-burnout-warning-signs-that-you-need-help/</guid>
      <description>You knew when you signed up for the job that being a doctor would be stressful. What you didn’t know was just how stressful it would be. Just a few years into your career, you’ve found yourself feeling fatigued, detached, and even depressed. Though normal on some level, given your profession, these symptoms are all red flags that you’re mentally and physically drained. Doctor burnout has become a trending topic lately, and with good reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control Your Pain Without Medication Using The Tens Machine</title>
      <link>/2018/07/26/control-your-pain-without-medication-using-the-tens-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 23:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/26/control-your-pain-without-medication-using-the-tens-machine/</guid>
      <description>The patients who are suffering from pain cannot have better news than this, that they will be no more suffering from pain. The relief from the pain of any type decreases the anxiety level of the body and sometimes it can make the person go to sleep who was having sleepless nights for days together. The patients who are suffering from periodic pain can really feel the relief from the pain with the use of TENS machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EHR Printing: Security Concerns Associated with Healthcare Organizations</title>
      <link>/2018/07/22/ehr-printing-security-concerns-associated-with-healthcare-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 17:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/22/ehr-printing-security-concerns-associated-with-healthcare-organizations/</guid>
      <description>Digital Transformation in the Healthcare Industry As the “going digital” trend rapidly gains popularity across the corporate world, industries across the board are looking to digital transformation to answer their security, workflow efficiency and productivity problems! The healthcare industry is at the forefront of this shift towards a digital world! With the healthcare industry hosting dynamic, fast-paced, and complex work environments, requiring up to the minute patient data, healthcare organizations were looking for an all-encompassing solution to their challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Things You May Not Know About Trichotillomania</title>
      <link>/2018/07/22/5-things-you-may-not-know-about-trichotillomania/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 14:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/22/5-things-you-may-not-know-about-trichotillomania/</guid>
      <description>For the few people out there, who know what trichotillomania is, their knowledge is limited, and they may not fully understand the condition. They know it has something to do with pulling out your hair. But they don’t know what causes it. And they don’t know that it’s an uncontrollable compulsion.
The vast majority of people, however, have no idea what trichotillomania is. This leads to misunderstanding and misconceptions about this very real condition that affects over 2% of the population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Depression Confession Group Tells The World About Mental Health</title>
      <link>/2018/07/22/a-depression-confession-group-tells-the-world-about-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/22/a-depression-confession-group-tells-the-world-about-mental-health/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest problems keeping people from seeking help for depression is the stigma attached to mental health issues. Now a group of people have gotten together for an event, The Depression Confessions, which RDNewsNow called, “a one-day consortium” that was streamed online for anyone who wanted to tune in.
An event like this felt like the perfect way to shine a light on the critical mental health issues and topics that many felt afraid to address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ED Treatment Information Center Launches Study of the Impact of Erectile Dysfunction on Men’s Partners: Interview With Robert Nicholson</title>
      <link>/2018/06/27/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners-interview-with-robert-nicholson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 18:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/27/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners-interview-with-robert-nicholson/</guid>
      <description>As part of its ongoing research efforts to assess the impact of erectile dysfunction, the ED Treatment Information Center has launched a new online survey targeting the partners of men suffering from ED. __We thus decided to interview Robert Nicholson to learn more about ED.
1. Can you tell us more about the ED Treatment Information Center? 
The Center grew out of my own experience. Two years ago, I was diagnosed with prostate cancer, and had my prostate removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for Your Dentist Appointment: Tips from North York Dentists</title>
      <link>/posts/prepare-for-your-dentist-appointment-tips-from-north-york-dentists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 07:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/prepare-for-your-dentist-appointment-tips-from-north-york-dentists/</guid>
      <description>For most of us, visiting the dental clinic is never much fun, especially if you are concerned about your teeth. To be honest, even when your dental clinic is a happy place, worrying about the whole event is perfectly normal. But it needn’t be. This article looks at the best way to prepare for your trip to your dentist and should help you get in a better frame of mind. Thanks to these proven tips, that next visit to your North York dental clinic will be a lot more fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look After Your Smile in 4 Easy Steps and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/look-after-your-smile-in-4-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 02:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/look-after-your-smile-in-4-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Nobody can honestly say that they enjoy those trips to the dentist, but they are part and parcel of modern life. However, that isn’t to say that we can’t do something to make them less of an issue. By looking after your teeth, you can keep them for the whole of your life and also minimise the pain and discomfort that we associate with poor dental hygiene. This short article offers 4 proven tips that will ensure that your smile stays just as beautiful as it is today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ED Treatment Information Center Launches Study of the Impact of Erectile Dysfunction on Men’s Partners</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners/</guid>
      <description>Contact: Robert Nicholson
Phone: +1-408-431-0674
Email: Robert@edtreatment.info
Approximately 30 million men in the United States suffer from erectile dysfunction, but it is often not recognized as a serious medical condition.
As part of its ongoing research efforts to assess the impact of erectile dysfunction, the ED Treatment Information Center has launched a new online survey targeting the partners of men suffering from ED. The survey takes about 5 minutes to complete, and is completely anonymous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Tips to Amplify Your Patient Satisfaction Surveys</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/4-tips-to-amplify-your-patient-satisfaction-surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 03:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/4-tips-to-amplify-your-patient-satisfaction-surveys/</guid>
      <description>Patient satisfaction surveys are growing in popularity among healthcare organizations as the United States health system continues its transition to value-based care. A well-designed and distributed survey can help you discover hidden issues or gems in your organization’s care system. It can also provide useful insights on whether you’re meeting patient expectations. If done right, your patient satisfaction survey can be a key player in building a satisfying and cohesive experience for patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Ways Technology is Changing the Fitness Industry</title>
      <link>/2018/03/17/7-ways-technology-is-changing-the-fitness-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 03:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/17/7-ways-technology-is-changing-the-fitness-industry/</guid>
      <description>Technology today has touched the biggest as well the smallest facet of life. From the involvement of technical upgrade into our daily routine to the use of technology in the fields like science and medicine – the technology has changed our entire perspective towards the things and today we do not look them at the way as we did in the good old days. From mobile phones to internet to speedy cars – technology is anywhere and everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truths About KetoCaNa – Is It Really Safe To Take It?!, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/truths-about-ketocana-is-it-really-safe-to-take-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 01:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/truths-about-ketocana-is-it-really-safe-to-take-it/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, getting a good figure has become an obsession for individuals, no matter what their gender or age is. To obtain a fit and attractive body, it is seen that people go beyond their limits and try everything comes their way without knowing that some stuff can have negative impacts on the body, especially the internal organs. But the madness of losing extra kilos or pounds overpowers every other aspect of their lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbal Teas and Their Health-related Role, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/21/herbal-teas-and-their-health-related-role-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 08:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/21/herbal-teas-and-their-health-related-role-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Despite the increasing variety of drugs, you can now access for various health problems, often, certain conditions are not that easily treatable, or you might not want to deal with the side effects they come with and end up not taking them all together. While they might not provide the same effects as medicine, teas have shown their benefits on people’s health for a long time, and healthcare specialists recommend their regular consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Boost Your Skills as a Medical Professional</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-boost-your-skills-as-a-medical-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 23:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-boost-your-skills-as-a-medical-professional/</guid>
      <description>Physicians and nurses are vital for keeping our healthcare system functioning, and as a result many people rely on them every day for their healthcare needs. Becoming a medical professional requires rigorous training over a period of years too, and that’s a hallmark of quality that patients and colleagues can trust. But how do physicians and others learn about the latest advances in medical technology, for example, or the outcomes of major pieces of research?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alphabet Soup of Value-Based Care Began Bubbling 40 Years Ago</title>
      <link>/posts/the-alphabet-soup-of-value-based-care-began-bubbling-40-years-ago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 23:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-alphabet-soup-of-value-based-care-began-bubbling-40-years-ago/</guid>
      <description>The head-spinning changes occurring in healthcare’s seismic shift from fee-for-service reimbursement to value-based care payment models has led to an ocean of patient and health data, along with an alphabet soup of colorful acronyms. Surely, the change has been rapid – and frequent – and a challenge for physicians and nurses, administrators, and the entire roster of clinic, health system, and hospital staffs. So fast, it seems, that it’s easy to image the change began occurring overnight, as if it crept up on us under cover of darkness, looming in the pre-dawn shadows and waiting to pounce at first light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have You Implemented a HIPAA Compliant Security Awareness Training Program?</title>
      <link>/2018/06/17/have-you-implemented-a-hipaa-compliant-security-awareness-training-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 22:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/17/have-you-implemented-a-hipaa-compliant-security-awareness-training-program/</guid>
      <description>All companies must take steps to prevent cyber-attacks and data breaches, but in healthcare this is especially important. Cybercriminals are targeting healthcare organizations to gain access to protected health information – Full sets of health records, especially those containing Social Security numbers and health insurance information, carry a high price on the black market.
Healthcare providers are heavily reliant on electronic data, access to which is needed for healthcare operations and to provide quality care to patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior Authorization Services</title>
      <link>/posts/prior-authorization-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 22:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/prior-authorization-services/</guid>
      <description>Prior authorization is essential for revenue yet creates an onerous burden on physician practices. When surveyed, 86 percent of physicians said their prior authorization requirements had increased over the past year. Seventy-five percent believe that prior authorization places “high or extremely high” burdens on them and their staff. Prior authorization requirements have increased to the point where 41 percent of physicians say they spend up to 20 hours each week on those tasks alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Software Platform Helps Practices Increase Revenue Through Enhanced Reimbursement</title>
      <link>/posts/new-software-platform-helps-practices-increase-revenue-through-enhanced-reimbursement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 22:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-software-platform-helps-practices-increase-revenue-through-enhanced-reimbursement/</guid>
      <description>CHARLESTON, SC, June 4, 2018 – SE Healthcare is excited to announce the official rollout of the Reimbursement Effectiveness Platform, the newest component of the company’s Physician Empowerment Suite, created for 26 individual specialties. SE is a healthcare technology company offering solutions to healthcare organizations through data analytics tools designed to improve safety, quality, reputation, risk mitigation, and reimbursement. The Physician Empowerment Suite (PES) is comprised of three additional components: The Patient Experience Platform, which helps healthcare providers foster a patient-centric environment and enhance reputation; The Clinical Effectiveness Platform, which assesses a provider’s clinical performance and areas of potential risks; and The Performance Improvement Tools, a set of just-in-time learning modules with educational tools and videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Success in Value-based Care: 7 Stages of the Health Data Life Cycle</title>
      <link>/posts/keys-to-success-in-value-based-care-7-stages-of-the-health-data-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 20:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/keys-to-success-in-value-based-care-7-stages-of-the-health-data-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>Back in the day – the late 1960s, when social norms and the face of America was rapidly changing – a familiar public service announcement began preceding the nightly news cast. “It’s 10 p.m. Do you know where your children are?” Today, as the healthcare landscape changes rapidly with a seismic shift from the fee-for-service payment model to value-based care models, there’s a similar but new clarion call for quality healthcare: “It’s 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Solutions in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/02/22/benefits-of-an-ehr-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 19:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/22/benefits-of-an-ehr-system/</guid>
      <description>While the principles of blockchain were first used in the world of finance as the technology that permitted Bitcoin to function, it has applications for many other industries, including healthcare.
With blockchain there&amp;rsquo;s no one central administrator; however, it comes with exceptional security advantages since records are distributed across a network of repeated databases, which are always synchronized. Users are only able to update the block they have access to, and such updates become repeated across the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dr. Mark Mckenna Went from Natural Disaster to OVME Launch</title>
      <link>/posts/how-dr-mark-mckenna-went-from-natural-disaster-to-ovme-launch-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-dr-mark-mckenna-went-from-natural-disaster-to-ovme-launch-comments/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Mark McKenna: Looking at the Future of the Good Doctor’s Motivation &amp;#8211; Show Girls Music - Jul 6, 2018
[…] he is also greeted by an enormous amount of support from his family. This is a cornerstone of any successful businessman, balance. His work in medical aesthetics is nowhere near done so it will be interesting to see […] Dr. Mark McKenna: Changing the Way That People Experience Medicine &amp;#8211; Jae Ink Speaks - Jul 6, 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dr. Mark Mckenna Went from Natural Disaster to OVME Launch</title>
      <link>/posts/how-dr-mark-mckenna-went-from-natural-disaster-to-ovme-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-dr-mark-mckenna-went-from-natural-disaster-to-ovme-launch/</guid>
      <description>It’s difficult to be a successful entrepreneur. Most people will never manage to add that to their list of achievements. But it’s even more difficult to be a successful entrepreneur in the face of disaster. Still, that’s the record of Dr. Mark McKenna. Whenever he has been faced with potential failure – whenever disaster has stood in his way – he has managed to pick himself up. Not only that, but he has excelled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Lab Requisition Online</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-get-a-lab-requisition-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 17:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-get-a-lab-requisition-online/</guid>
      <description>Virtual doctor appointments allow you to seek help as long as you have a phone and an Internet connection. But what happens if you need lab work? There are ways to get a lab requisition online and have the results in hand quickly. Here is how the process works. Begin With a Virtual Physician Visit If you have a virtual consultation with your doctor and tests are needed, the process for setting up a lab requisition begins while that visit is in progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Let Go of Self-Limiting Beliefs</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-let-go-of-self-limiting-beliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 23:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-let-go-of-self-limiting-beliefs/</guid>
      <description>Do you tend to focus on what others think of you instead of what you think of yourself? This could be what is getting in the way of you achieving your goals. According to research by the University of Scranton, 92% of the people don’t achieve their goals. The reason most people do not succeed in achieving their goals is that they do not set specific and challenging goals. Not having clarity around the goals and not challenging yourself enough minimizes the chances of hitting the mark, preventing us from being as successful as we could be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Things That Are Destroying Your Health and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/07/5-things-that-are-destroying-your-health-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 22:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/07/5-things-that-are-destroying-your-health-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Healthy nutrition is important to lead an energetic and happy life. However, most of us don’t know what incorporates a healthy diet. Lack of knowledge makes us eat foods that are unhealthy and largely contribute towards damaging our health. The main reason to opt for unhealthy foods is crave. It’s daunting to resist taste, especially when something is right before you sitting on the table. We speak of processed foods and foods that contain excessive amounts of sugars and sodium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Devices Every Senior Needs</title>
      <link>/posts/medical-devices-every-senior-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 18:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/medical-devices-every-senior-needs/</guid>
      <description>Technology has made incredible advances in how it improves the way we live: The whole point behind technology is to make life more convenient, and this means that the medical sector is part of this. Here are some medical devices that every senior needs to have if they want to make their life just a little bit easier with the help of some great technology. A Smartphone Most people don’t think of a smartphone as a medical device, but with a couple adaptations and the right apps installed on it, it can quickly become one of the greatest health aids that you have at your disposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right Population Health Analytics to Transform the Patient Experience</title>
      <link>/posts/the-right-population-health-analytics-to-transform-the-patient-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 17:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-right-population-health-analytics-to-transform-the-patient-experience/</guid>
      <description>Consider a situation where healthcare is not just an industry term- a situation where EHRs are not an integral part of physicians schedule but just a support to providing care. All considered, imagine a situation where patient-centric care actually involves the patient, and patient engagement is not just a buzzword but a reality. Unfortunately, all these imaginations were supposed to be a reality, but still, healthcare managers and organizations are struggling with the problems such as the lack of patients’ adherence to medication, varying trends in the population health, and a lot more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dental Work and Tinnitus: Here’s What You Need to Know, and How Technology is Changing Dentistry</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/dental-work-and-tinnitus-heres-what-you-need-to-know-and-how-technology-is-improving-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 17:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/dental-work-and-tinnitus-heres-what-you-need-to-know-and-how-technology-is-improving-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to our teeth, there is nothing more important than taking good care of them. Unless you want a mouth full of fake teeth by the time you are 40, you need to brush, floss, rinse, and do it on a regular basis. However, there is only so much that you can do to take proper care of your teeth. Perhaps the most important part is that trip to the dentist that you take every six months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Mexico Hospital Battles Addiction with Health Information Technology Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/new-mexico-hospital-battles-addiction-with-health-information-technology-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 16:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-mexico-hospital-battles-addiction-with-health-information-technology-apps/</guid>
      <description>McKinley County, New Mexico, is the namesake of the assassinated 25 U.S. President William McKinley. Many locals, particularly those Native Americans of Navajo decent living on reservations, have also been the victim of assassination, but in character in addition to physical attacks. Three decades ago Gallup, New Mexico, which borders on the Navajo Reservation, was known as &amp;ldquo;Drunk Town, USA.&amp;rdquo; For many years Northwest New Mexico’s Gallup ranked number one nationally in the number of alcohol-related deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Eating Becomes an Addiction and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/when-eating-becomes-an-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/when-eating-becomes-an-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Food is a necessity of life and growth. It is also a source of comfort, pleasure and social engagement. But for some individuals, the need to consume food is compulsive and uncontrollable. It has become as addictive to them as drugs are to substance abusers._
Food full of fat, sugar and sometimes salt, triggers chemicals in the brain that create feelings of pleasure, like dopamine, a neurotransmitter that plays a vital role in the brain’s reward system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Activity in Assisted Living and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/the-importance-of-activity-in-assisted-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 08:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-importance-of-activity-in-assisted-living/</guid>
      <description>If you’re trying to choose an appropriate assisted living facility for yourself or an aging loved one, there are so many things to consider that it seems futile to read another article making recommendations about what you should look for in a center. However, today our team is here to help you consider how the majority of recommendations for having a fulfilling, happy stay in the assisted living center of your choice circle back to one thing: the level of appropriate physical activity offered to residents on a regular basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defective Medical Devices and How You Can File for a Lawsuit</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/defective-medical-devices-and-how-you-can-file-for-a-lawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 05:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/defective-medical-devices-and-how-you-can-file-for-a-lawsuit/</guid>
      <description>Breast implants may not only provide you with a good-looking figure; it can also lead you to file a defective product lawsuit against the person who implanted them in your breasts.
If you have had this problem after undergoing breast implant surgery and the implants its about time you act on the issue.
Implants, just like any other medical devices inserted into your body can create some side effects. Issues that may arise may not be defined at the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Groundbreaking Technological Innovations that Will Help You Manage COPD and Asthma</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/4-groundbreaking-technological-innovations-that-will-help-you-manage-copd-and-asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 21:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/4-groundbreaking-technological-innovations-that-will-help-you-manage-copd-and-asthma/</guid>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) includes lung disorders such as asthma and Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary under the broad classification of Chronic Respiratory Diseases (CRD). Patients suffering from any kind of CRD have trouble breathing because of damaged air sacs or alveoli, and airways like in the case of COPD. On the other hand, difficulty in respiration because of allergens and other causes that inflame the airways is a condition called asthma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Technology Is Improving Sports Injury Prevention and Recovery</title>
      <link>/posts/how-technology-is-improving-sports-injury-prevention-and-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 20:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-technology-is-improving-sports-injury-prevention-and-recovery/</guid>
      <description>The sports injury is a very common thing. It affects a lot of players during their career as a sports person. With injuries being so common in any form of sports, it is imperative that it is understood and the recovery should be improved. Researchers have been trying to put in cutting-edge technology to prevent injuries due to sports. There are many products in the market as well which can help improve the chances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Top Benefits of Sleep Dentistry</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/4-top-benefits-of-sleep-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 16:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/4-top-benefits-of-sleep-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>If you’re nervous about visiting the dentist or having a dental procedure performed, it may be worthwhile looking into sleep dentistry. Going to sleep during a dental procedure can help make the process much less stressful, as you won’t feel physically uncomfortable. In addition, a dentist can complete dental cleaning and other procedures much faster when the patient is sedated. There are a number of sedative types that can be offered by a sleep dentist, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Self Monitoring Help You to Track Brain Injury Symptoms?</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/can-self-monitoring-help-you-to-track-brain-injury-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 15:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/can-self-monitoring-help-you-to-track-brain-injury-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>Brain injuries can happen, in sports, at work, if you are in an accident – it’s possible to sustain an injury to the brain if you have had a bump on the head. What many people don’t know is that brain injury symptoms can become more apparent with time. While an initial visit to a&amp;amp;e might only give you a concussion diagnosis, ongoing symptoms might be missed if a patient does not familiarise themselves with things to watch for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMS’s Proposed PI Rule Changes is a Good Start, But Does it Address Enough?</title>
      <link>/2018/05/28/cmss-proposed-pi-rule-changes-is-a-good-start-but-does-it-address-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 01:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/28/cmss-proposed-pi-rule-changes-is-a-good-start-but-does-it-address-enough/</guid>
      <description>Federal healthcare organizations such as CMS have spent billions of dollars over the years trying to bridge the gap between medical data and quality patient care with interoperability requirements and data integration, the mesh used to try and bridge the gap. Many government rules have been written to address the type of mesh needed and many EHR companies have claimed to meet these government requirements and claim the throne of the ultimate mesh maker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors and Approaches to Be Considered While Designing IoT Gateways</title>
      <link>/2018/05/25/factors-and-approaches-to-be-considered-while-designing-iot-gateways/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 23:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/25/factors-and-approaches-to-be-considered-while-designing-iot-gateways/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging production-ready IoT gateway platforms and customizing them to achieve faster time to market and reduced cost for desired configurations and wireless connectivity options
As the trend for IoT is growing with the rising number of connected devices, the demand for IoT gateways has also increased significantly and will continue to grow exponentially in industries like Healthcare, Hospitality, Automotive, etc. The Market for IoT in Healthcare is supposed to increase by 56% each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Straightforward Advice About Providing Your Family a Healthy Diet, Especially When Your Child has Special Needs, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/straightforward-advice-about-providing-your-family-a-healthy-diet-especially-when-your-child-has-special-needs-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 22:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/straightforward-advice-about-providing-your-family-a-healthy-diet-especially-when-your-child-has-special-needs-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, a large number of families with children live with a hectic daily schedule of activities, appointments, and commitments. This type of lifestyle ensures that not only will it be difficult to sit down as a family to a healthy homemade dinner, but that the family’s meals are likely to be comprised of a considerable amount of take-out and frozen, prepackaged meals. It&amp;rsquo;s not a great surprise that these diets are typically unhealthy and may very well adversely impact your child’s health and wellness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 20 Foods You Can Have on Keto Diet That Make It Easy</title>
      <link>/2018/05/25/title-top-20-foods-you-can-have-on-keto-diet-that-make-it-easy-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 21:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/25/title-top-20-foods-you-can-have-on-keto-diet-that-make-it-easy-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Many might ask the question, why keto diet? Well, because it is not only effective in losing weight but also enhances your mental focus and helps in combating Diabetes Type II.
You must be thinking keto diet might mean eating tasteless boring food. Well, it’s not true. Keto is a complete diet. You can eat so many foods to meet your macros. There are many types of foods and dishes you can make to hit your daily fat, protein and carbs intake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological Solutions in Dentistry</title>
      <link>/posts/technological-solutions-in-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 20:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technological-solutions-in-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few decades, the field of dentistry among other medical disciplines (such as plastic surgery or medical education industry) has experienced a surge of technological advancements. It has not only made the work of dentists easier but visits to the dentist have become less worrisome. The dentistry technologies aim to make a visit to the dentist comfortable and painless while your oral health problems are addressed in full. With the many technologies utilized by renowned dental clinics like Bajars &amp;amp; Bajars to offer first class services to their patients, below are some of the most popular ones: Laser Dentistry It involves the use of laser beams for treatment and speeding up the dental treatment processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Technological Advancements Can Help Facilitate Geriatrics and Adaptive Ageing</title>
      <link>/posts/how-technological-advancements-can-help-facilitate-geriatrics-and-adaptive-ageing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 16:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-technological-advancements-can-help-facilitate-geriatrics-and-adaptive-ageing/</guid>
      <description>As the 21st century wears on, we now increasingly rely on technological advancements for the prevention, detection, and treatment of complex health issues of the elderly. As studies have shown (such as those performed by Dr. Steven Gundry of Gundry MD), the consumption of certain foods and substances such as Lectins affect our health and lends a hand to the development of diseases. Furthermore, as people age, physiological systems of the body begin to deteriorate and, which is accompanied by changes to structural and anatomical characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is a Weighted Blanket a Real Prospect for Anxiety-related Sleep Disorders? And Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/is-a-weighted-blanket-a-real-prospect-for-anxiety-related-sleep-disorders-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 23:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/is-a-weighted-blanket-a-real-prospect-for-anxiety-related-sleep-disorders-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>We talked about the alarming insomnia stats more times than we can count, and with a good reason. The increased prevalence over the past two decades has a much deeper impact on the healthcare system then one might think. It goes beyond sleep itself and affects both prevalence and occurrence of other costly health problems - anything from cardiovascular disease to neurological disorders. In the time span between 1995 and 2005, the connection was “blurry” at best, because of the other lifestyle habits affecting the numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Let Acne Hamper Your Skin Confidence and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/18/dont-let-acne-hamper-your-skin-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/18/dont-let-acne-hamper-your-skin-confidence/</guid>
      <description>In today’s hectic lifestyle, confidence is the only companion that can help a woman successfully deal with her everyday challenges and responsibilities. Confidence in a woman can come from various factors related to her personal achievements and skills. However, this same confidence can also get hampered by an unhealthy skin condition like acne.
Having blemish-free skin, on the other hand, does wonders to one’s confidence, at home and at work. This is called skin confidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips to Maximize KETO Diet Results and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/02/5-tips-to-maximize-keto-diet-results-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/02/5-tips-to-maximize-keto-diet-results-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>From weight loss, and better mental health to the prevention of some lifestyle diseases such as type II diabetes, and appetite control, the benefits that come with a perfect KETO diet are immeasurable. If you desire to live a healthy lifestyle that everyone is talking about, the nutritional value you will get from this diet is all you need – but you ought to do everything right. When most people decide to start a KETO diet, they will download recipes in their hundreds, follow them to the letter and expect results…well, amazing results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hordenine: Your Companion in Weight Loss and Some Weight Management Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/04/30/hordenine-your-companion-in-weight-loss-and-some-weight-management-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 22:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/30/hordenine-your-companion-in-weight-loss-and-some-weight-management-apps/</guid>
      <description>Are you someone who has never been able to reach your body weight goals? Well, you are not alone. There are millions of people who are unable to shed off those extra pounds off their body, no matter how much they try.
According to a 2017 study, published in Time, obesity now leads to more early preventable deaths in the US than smoking. This has fuelled the growth of the global weight-loss industry, including meal plans, diet pills and gym memberships, which has reached a value of $66.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How 3D Printing Has Transformed the Medical Sector</title>
      <link>/2018/04/28/how-3d-printing-has-transformed-the-medical-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 21:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/28/how-3d-printing-has-transformed-the-medical-sector/</guid>
      <description>3D printing has become the most sort out technology in the world currently. This has led to applications in different sectors of the economy. Due to its vast applications, 3D printing has transformed many lives in different ways. Is 3D printing applicable in the medical sector? Yes, currently the medical sector has embraced this technology in various ways. Also known as, ‘Rapid Prototyping’ 3D printing has enabled the creation of new objects similar to existing objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips to Help Teens Cope With Stress and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/04/26/tips-to-help-teens-cope-with-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 18:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/26/tips-to-help-teens-cope-with-stress/</guid>
      <description>Teens suffer high stress, and they need help to cope with it. The worst part is that they do not find many people to help them in coping with stress. This is because they are not willing to open up on this matter and get help. If you fall into this category and desperately need help, here are some tips that will help you cope with stress. 1. Get some sleep There are many things to do as a teenager and between homework, hanging out with friends and performing other activities; you need to find an excuse to get some sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Global Health Issues</title>
      <link>/2018/04/26/10-global-health-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 15:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/26/10-global-health-issues/</guid>
      <description>Humans have been battling with various communicable as well as non-communicable diseases since the ancient times.
The advancement of medical knowledge and technology has enabled the world to develop antiviral, antibiotics, vaccines and other methods to prevent and treat a large majority of these diseases.
According to the WHO report, there has been a decrease in the number of deaths due to infectious diseases like malaria and HIV as well better awareness amongst people about the risks of non-communicable diseases such as lung cancer, cardiovascular problems and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Generation Model for Addressing Crisis Behavioral Health in the ED</title>
      <link>/posts/next-generation-model-for-addressing-crisis-behavioral-health-in-the-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 23:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/next-generation-model-for-addressing-crisis-behavioral-health-in-the-ed/</guid>
      <description>Taking telepsychiatry strategies to the next level. The telemedicine revolution touches nearly every aspect of health care today. Notably, behavioral health was called out in a recent Forbes article as the sector within the industry experiencing the greatest impact. And hospital emergency departments (EDs) are taking note. In recent years, EDs have faced notable challenges meeting growing needs for mental and behavioral health services, particularly for crisis psychiatric care, amid severe professional shortages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Your EHR to Combat Substance Abuse</title>
      <link>/posts/leveraging-your-ehr-to-combat-substance-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 17:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/leveraging-your-ehr-to-combat-substance-abuse/</guid>
      <description>As the healthcare industry explores strategies to combat opioid dependency, it seems that technology could be of increasing value — if used correctly. Every day, we’re reminded in news headlines and scientific reports that we’re experiencing an opioid crisis in the United States. We’re also reminded that it’s only getting worse. An estimated two million Americans are addicted to opioids, such as prescription opioid pain relievers or heroin, according to the National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considering A Data-Led Approach To Pharmacology</title>
      <link>/2018/04/22/considering-a-data-led-approach-to-pharmacology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 02:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/22/considering-a-data-led-approach-to-pharmacology/</guid>
      <description>The American healthcare system is renowned worldwide for its quality, but is not without its problems. According to research by Johns Hopkins, 250,000 people die due to medical errors every year in the USA - and according to researcher Martin Makary, part of this is down to incorrect prescriptions. Seeking to counter this challenge is big data, technology and innovation; making the prescription process quicker, easier, and more precise.
Like many other industries, technology in the medical industry moves at breakneck speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-home Care Technology: The Future of Connected Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/04/22/what-you-can-use-for-home-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 02:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/22/what-you-can-use-for-home-health-care/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, there has been a lot of controversy in the healthcare system (high cost and declining quality of care) with more patients discharged for a home health care setup.
This is a matter of concern especially since recovery in the home setting is mostly dependent on someone else for continued care. Seniors living alone, for example, face this risk, medications can be missed, or a fall could happen in between (infrequent) visits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Content Ideas for Your Blog in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/04/19/creative-content-ideas-for-your-blog-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 21:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/19/creative-content-ideas-for-your-blog-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>When writing content for your blog the first concern you should have is attracting readers! Well especially when you are writing about healthcare, this is only possible if your blog has high rankings in the search engines. Search engine optimization is essential and if you&amp;rsquo;re not listed on the first page of search results the number of people viewing your blog goes down. Modern search engine optimization is not driven by keywords but by useful content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deal with a Drug Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-deal-with-a-drug-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 17:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-deal-with-a-drug-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Drug addiction is one of the most insidious aspects of our modern society, with an increasing amount of addicted individuals. If you find yourself grappling with drug addiction, then you most likely have a tough road ahead. Here are some of the things that you should evaluate. Learn About the Drug Knowing about the drug and what it does to your body might just put you off. Your body is a finely tuned machine and adding these chemicals into it can send it into disarray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getsafe Launches Pioneering Health Insurance API</title>
      <link>/2018/04/16/getsafe-launches-pioneering-health-insurance-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 23:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/16/getsafe-launches-pioneering-health-insurance-api/</guid>
      <description>Heidelberg 15.03.2018 - Getsafe is now offering developers an API for integrating insurance products into third-party apps, the first to include health insurance options.
Through Getsafe’s new API, healthcare providers such as medical offices are now able to offer easily accessible health insurance products to their patients, particularly those who avoid booking much-needed appointments because of high costs. Patients now have an easy way to get instant coverage prior to booking their appointment, avoiding potentially costly surprises after their procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Dental Digital Health Technology More Advanced Than Other Healthcare Specialties?</title>
      <link>/2018/03/29/why-is-dental-digital-health-technology-more-advanced-than-other-healthcare-specialties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 19:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/29/why-is-dental-digital-health-technology-more-advanced-than-other-healthcare-specialties/</guid>
      <description>Technology has helped achieve unimaginable feats in the field of health and medicine. Hi-tech equipment and cutting-edge techniques are helping doctors and healthcare specialists make stunning medical breakthroughs every day. While these advancements are being observed in all perspectives of healthcare, its highest benefactor seems to be the dental department.
Dentistry has developed like no other area of medicine in the last decade. If you wake up in the middle of the night with a sensitive tooth problem, the issue can be permanently resolved during the (same) day That kind of superfast prognosis and diagnosis is, however, either non-existent or extremely rare for other problematic diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Digital Dental Implants</title>
      <link>/posts/the-benefits-of-digital-dental-implants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 18:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-benefits-of-digital-dental-implants/</guid>
      <description>Dentistry has evolved a lot in the last years, one of the most performant branches of this industry being implantology. With greater access to international courses and studies, more and more dentists started specializing in different areas and offer improved services to their clients seeking for the perfect smile. Nowadays, this perfect smile can be obtained with the help of dental implants which are gradually replacing the traditional crowns. Dental implants have more benefits than other teeth restoration methods, however they are also more expensive due to the technology involved at this stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Calculate Your Compensations After a Personal Injury</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-calculate-your-compensations-after-a-personal-injury/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 18:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-calculate-your-compensations-after-a-personal-injury/</guid>
      <description>Speed, lack of attention, difficult weather conditions, drinking and driving are all precursors of accidents which often lead to personal injuries. Persons who suffer personal injuries do not only go through physical pain, but also emotional stress and the effects do not stop here. Temporary or permanent loss of employment, medical expenses, disruptions of the day-to-day activities and huge discomfort are just a few of the consequences; therefore, it is totally understandable for these persons to claim compensations after an accident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from HIMSS 2018: The Need for Cloud, “Killer Apps” and Connectivity, But Are They Already Here?</title>
      <link>/posts/lessons-from-himss-2018-the-need-for-cloud-killer-apps-and-connectivity-but-are-they-already-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 22:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lessons-from-himss-2018-the-need-for-cloud-killer-apps-and-connectivity-but-are-they-already-here/</guid>
      <description>By Donald Voltz, MD, Aultman Hospital, Department of Anesthesiology, Medical Director of the Main Operating Room, Assistant Professor of Anesthesiology, Case Western Reserve University and Northeast Ohio Medical University In his HIMSS keynote address, Alphabet’s former executive chairman and now current technical advisor Eric Schmidt warned attendees that the “future of healthcare lies in the need for killer apps.” But he also cautioned that the transition to a better digitally connected health future isn&amp;rsquo;t just one killer app, but a system of apps working together in the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitamins and Supplements: Why Your Child May Need Them (and some useful apps)</title>
      <link>/2018/03/27/vitamins-and-supplements-why-your-child-may-need-them-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 22:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/27/vitamins-and-supplements-why-your-child-may-need-them-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Every parent wants their child to grow up to be healthy and strong. One of the most common ways to do this is to make sure that your children are getting the proper vitamins and nutrients they need through the foods and beverages you serve them. Though most parents do try to serve their children healthy meals, sometimes, diet alone isn’t enough to provide their growing bodies with the fuel they need to properly develop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerful Ways to Beat Psychological Trauma (Including Technology)</title>
      <link>/2018/03/27/5-powerful-ways-to-beat-psychological-trauma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 21:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/27/5-powerful-ways-to-beat-psychological-trauma/</guid>
      <description>If you are like most people, then chances are you have experienced psychological trauma without knowing it. We have experienced an intense, confusing and frightening pain as a result of a horrific event. Each time we remember such event, a shock runs through our spine, and we feel that cloud of negativity loom over us.
If you have a similar experience, you should know that you are not alone. Many have had this experience, and they have overcome it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Artificial Intelligence on Healthcare</title>
      <link>/posts/the-impact-of-artificial-intelligence-on-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 19:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-impact-of-artificial-intelligence-on-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Research shows that there is an increase of chronic diseases globally. In case of an outbreak of an infectious disease like Ebola, there is usually a rapid spread throughout the entire world. We must find ways of handling the quick spread of outbreaks to reduce the number of people who might contract the disease. In recent years, researchers have made advancements in detecting and diagnosing of chronic diseases, thus reducing overall treatment costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enriching: The Record Retrieval Services In 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/03/25/enriching-the-record-retrieval-services-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/25/enriching-the-record-retrieval-services-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Locating a particular document, file, or record, and delivering it for use is nothing but record retrieval. Multiple record retrieval companies provide retrieval services to claim assistants, also attorneys and medical professionals as well. Complying to the HIPAA norms, processing, and handling required documents including, but not limited to authorization to release medical records, notices, notice of privacy practices, these record retrieval companies collect medical documents either manually, electronically using faxes or emails and even directly accessing EMR for document downloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How You Can Find Cost-Effective Cosmetic Dentistry</title>
      <link>/posts/how-you-can-find-cost-effective-cosmetic-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 16:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-you-can-find-cost-effective-cosmetic-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>The revolutionary buzzword in the realm of pride is cosmetic dentistry. This is an industry of dental care which is fast gaining an enormous amount of recognition, thanks to people who are prepared to go all the way to get that billion dollar smile. This particular effort consists of treatments like smile designing, tooth veneers and in some instances, even teeth implants. For this reason, it is commonly a very costly method without a doubt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology to Shape Healthcare in 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-to-shape-healthcare-in-2018-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-to-shape-healthcare-in-2018-comments/</guid>
      <description>How Technology Is Revolutionizing Plastic Surgery - May 4, 2018
[…] This 200% increase compared to the year 2000 can be attributed to technological advancements. Technological innovation and advancements in healthcare have shaped the evolution of plastic surgery in the last century. Evidence suggests that a high […] How Technology Is Revolutionizing Plastic Surgery &amp;#8211; My Blog - Jun 4, 2018
[…] This 200% increase compared to the year 2000 can be attributed to technological advancements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology to Shape Healthcare in 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-to-shape-healthcare-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-to-shape-healthcare-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Technology is providing ever-smarter ways to do things, and professionals in healthcare are just as keen to find uses for it as those in industry. A catalyst for this is the demands put on the healthcare system by a growing population and rising life expectancies. To maintain standards of care and improve outcomes for patients, hospitals and medical centers need to adopt new technologies that enable them to work more efficiently and effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling the Challenges of Patient Engagement with Healthcare Data</title>
      <link>/posts/tackling-the-challenges-of-patient-engagement-with-healthcare-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 22:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tackling-the-challenges-of-patient-engagement-with-healthcare-data/</guid>
      <description>Effective population health management has made it imperative that patients have an equal footing in the matters of their health. Access to comprehensive, reliable data is one vital ingredient healthcare organizations require for effectively engaging patients. The challenge that lies before this foundational step is the lack of a unified healthcare data platform, a single source-of-truth connecting multiple healthcare data sources. The universe of healthcare data is dotted with individual EHRs, billing files, claims data- we are data rich, but almost paralyzed when it comes to collecting and analyzing this mound of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Technology Helping People With Dementia Live Better Lives</title>
      <link>/posts/modern-technology-helping-people-with-dementia-live-better-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 21:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/modern-technology-helping-people-with-dementia-live-better-lives/</guid>
      <description>Family members start to see the warning signs early on, but they put it to the back of their minds. Eventually, you’re not left with much of a choice. You need to take your relative to the doctor and you already know what they’re going to say. The person you care about has dementia, so over time they’ll begin to slip away. Thankfully, modern technology allows those suffering from the disease to lead a better life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Muslim Health Professionals Organize National Conference for Health Professionals</title>
      <link>/2018/03/15/american-muslim-health-professionals-organize-national-conference-for-health-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 17:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/15/american-muslim-health-professionals-organize-national-conference-for-health-professionals/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge, MA - Over 100 health professionals will convene on Saturday, March 31, 2018 in a national conference organized by American Muslim Health Professionals (AMHP) and the Cambridge Public Health Department. The objective of the conference is to foster dialogue and leverage the skills and talents of Muslim professionals from diverse sectors across AMHP’s core areas of focus: mental health; advocacy and advancing access to health care; and career and professional development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare IT Trends to Watch Through 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/03/15/healthcare-it-trends-to-watch-through-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 15:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/15/healthcare-it-trends-to-watch-through-2018/</guid>
      <description>Technological innovations and developments in IT are transforming the healthcare industry at every level. From fostering better relationships between patient and caregiver, to facilitating improved and more valuable data analysis, the potential rewards offered by modern technology for all stakeholders is significant. Here are three examples of areas of technology that are changing the face of healthcare for the better.
Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Artificial intelligence, which can be defined simply as the simulation of human intelligence processes (such as learning and reasoning) by computer systems, has been disrupting other industries for several years, with tech, telecoms, and financial services leading the charge in this space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Long Does It Take to Settle a Personal Injury Claim?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-long-does-it-take-to-settle-a-personal-injury-claim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 14:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-long-does-it-take-to-settle-a-personal-injury-claim/</guid>
      <description>Before getting into this article, it is very important that you understand that there are far too many variable factors at play here for the exact timeframe to be estimated accurately without even knowing the details of any particular case. These are only average approximations based on the general proceedings and they are to be taken as such. Nevertheless, the time estimations are fairly dependable under normal circumstances and they should mentally prepare you for what’s to come once you hire your injury lawyer and file your lawsuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips For Preventing Tech neck</title>
      <link>/posts/tips-for-preventing-tech-neck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 14:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tips-for-preventing-tech-neck/</guid>
      <description>Being dependent on technology, tech neck is a common issue amongst people nowadays. Most of the people spending excessive time on mobile phones, tablets, laptops, desktops and other electronic devices are faced with the issue of tech neck. The good news is that there are certain tips that can help you in preventing the issue and feel good about your neck forever. 1. Opting for a Physiotherapy session With a quick visit to a Physio, it will be easy to understand that you can feel good about your neck and give yourself an opportunity to stay relaxed while enjoying the session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Stay Motivated and Meet Your Fitness Goals, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/03/13/4-ways-to-stay-motivated-and-meet-your-fitness-goals-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 19:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/13/4-ways-to-stay-motivated-and-meet-your-fitness-goals-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve already set your fitness goals and started an exercise routine — but you struggle with motivation. Some mornings, you can think of a dozen different reasons to skip your workout, and staying in bed sounds like a much better option. If that sounds like you, give one of the following tips a try:
Get Someone Else Involved
One of the easiest ways to stay motivated is to get someone else involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Benefits of Social Media in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/03/13/5-benefits-of-social-media-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/13/5-benefits-of-social-media-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Technology, media and the internet has been having a huge impact in our lives since a long time now. But the sudden rise in social media usage has brought in much better and more advanced opportunities to business, marketing and general public awareness. The popularity of social media continues to increase and demographics show that the most growing users of social media are individuals aged 45-54.
Gone are the days when healthcare could only be provided through a practitioner by seeing them face-to-face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Importance of Videos: How Healthcare Businesses Can Take Advantage</title>
      <link>/2018/03/04/growing-importance-of-videos-how-healthcare-businesses-can-take-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 22:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/04/growing-importance-of-videos-how-healthcare-businesses-can-take-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Google says that by focusing on searches and understanding users&amp;rsquo; intent behind them, you can better target your ideal audience online. According to Google, videos can achieve greater lift and brand recall during search. In fact, it can give up to a 53% lift in: landing page visits, expressions of interests (EOIs), and key performance indicators (KPIs) – generally leading to conversions.
With 77% of healthcare inquiries beginning on search engines and patients referencing at least 12 different sources of information before deciding where to get care, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial for you to be present among those 12 sources, and to provide content that is highly engaging and influential for those prospective patients to choose you as their provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bundled Payment May be Waning, but the Need for Care Coordination is Not</title>
      <link>/2018/02/26/bundled-payment-may-waning-need-care-coordination-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 06:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/26/bundled-payment-may-waning-need-care-coordination-not/</guid>
      <description>Last month, the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Service (CMS) released its final rule, which dramatically changes bundled payment requirements for many organizations. The rule cancels the hip fracture and cardiac bundled payment models that were set to launch on Jan. 1, 2018, as well as diminishes the Comprehensive Care for Joint Replacement (CJR) model. Now the rule requires only 34 geographic areas to participate in CJR instead of the previously-mandated 67The remaining areas will have the option to voluntarily take part going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for a Better Night&#39;s Sleep and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 05:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps-comments/</guid>
      <description>8 pași pentru un somn odihnitor - Ghid practic pentru a te trezi odihnit - May 2, 2018
[…] HealthcareGuys, Mayo Clinic, HelpGuide, Sleep […] 8 pași pentru un somn odihnitor | Date despre E-uri. Ai grija ce consumi! - May 1, 2018
[…] HealthcareGuys, Mayo Clinic, HelpGuide, Sleep […] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for a Better Night&#39;s Sleep and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/02/26/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 05:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/26/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to getting a better night sleep, the mattresses and pillow companies on television will fool you into thinking that those are the only things preventing you from sleeping through the night. But there are actually a lot of factors out there that affect your quality of sleep. Here are ten tips that will help you get a better night sleep, and some useful apps you can use to aid you in your sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to Track Marketing Performance Without Violating HIPAA? Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>/2018/02/24/want-to-track-marketing-performance-without-violating-hipaa-heres-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 03:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/24/want-to-track-marketing-performance-without-violating-hipaa-heres-how/</guid>
      <description>Tracking your online marketing performance to gain a greater understanding of ROI and ultimately optimize your efforts is essential to the success of your campaigns. But as a healthcare provider, your patients’ safety and privacy are your #1 priorities. So, you face a unique challenge: How do you track your marketing and performance efforts without violating HIPAA?
Start with Protected Health Information (PHI)
First things first: You need to find out if the technology you want to implement collects or stores PHI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Use of Existing Tech Can Boost Patient Engagement</title>
      <link>/posts/smart-use-of-existing-tech-can-boost-patient-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 01:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/smart-use-of-existing-tech-can-boost-patient-engagement/</guid>
      <description>Many healthcare providers in the U.S. wish their patients would take more accountability for managing their health. According to a West survey, 96 percent of providers feel frustrated when patients do not actively participate in their own healthcare. In a perfect world, every patient would follow their care plan exactly as instructed after leaving their doctor’s office. However, as physicians know, this isn’t always as easy as it seems. Although it is frustrating for healthcare providers to see patients not heeding advice or doing what is necessary to manage their health after providers have spent time examining them, answering questions and prescribing treatments, healthcare providers should not be discouraged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Smartphones in Encouraging the Continuance of Physical Therapy</title>
      <link>/posts/the-role-of-smartphones-in-encouraging-the-continuance-of-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 06:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-role-of-smartphones-in-encouraging-the-continuance-of-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>If you have undergone surgery or suffered a rather severe injury, one of the things you will need to do is attend physical therapy. You will also be expected to do various exercises on your own. Now, physical therapy has been proven to greatly improve strength, dexterity, and muscle tone. The problem, however, lies with people actually sticking to with their therapy until the end. Well, fortunately, technology – and the average smartphone – has begun to play a much greater role in this type of recovery which has made things easier for patients and therapists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of an EHR System</title>
      <link>/2018/02/22/benefits-of-an-ehr-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 05:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/22/benefits-of-an-ehr-system/</guid>
      <description>Once considered a luxury, EHR Software has become a necessity for modern providers who want to stay viable in today&amp;rsquo;s healthcare climate. If your practice has yet to transition to electronic health records, learn how this efficient technology can help save time, money and, in certain instances, lives.
EHR Benefits to Practitioners
A properly integrated EHR system can be a godsend for medical practitioners who want to improve patient care and streamline operational efficiencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Unpaid Medical Bills Putting a Blemish on your Credit Report?</title>
      <link>/2018/02/22/are-unpaid-medical-bills-putting-a-blemish-on-your-credit-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 05:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/22/are-unpaid-medical-bills-putting-a-blemish-on-your-credit-report/</guid>
      <description>Credit reports hold a lot of valuable information about us and our day-to-day. They show our paying history, our debt, our loans, bills that we have, or haven&amp;rsquo;t, paid on time, and the number of credit cards or accounts that we have opened up under our name. While credit reports can be a great asset, they also can contain information that can prove to make purchases or obtaining loans a lot more difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Your Patient Portal is a Must on Your New Year&#39;s Resolutions List</title>
      <link>/posts/optimizing-your-patient-portal-is-a-must-on-your-new-years-resolutions-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 04:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/optimizing-your-patient-portal-is-a-must-on-your-new-years-resolutions-list/</guid>
      <description>Although patient portals have the potential to not only meet requirements, but also provide a delightful user experience, a report released in March 2017 shows these portals seem to be popular with care providers, but not so much with patients. The U.S. Government Accountability Office discovered 88 percent of hospitals and 87 percent of physician practices offered patient portals. However, only 15 percent of hospitals’ and 30 percent of physicians practices’ patients accessed medical information through the portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telehealth, Post Net Neutrality: How We&#39;re Moving Forward</title>
      <link>/posts/telehealth-post-net-neutrality-how-were-moving-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/telehealth-post-net-neutrality-how-were-moving-forward/</guid>
      <description>In December, the FCC voted to repeal its net neutrality rules, which would essentially give service providers the green light to start charging for differentiated Internet speed access. While efforts to block this are underway in Congress, and states are taking legal actions, healthcare providers have good reason to be concerned.
In defense of the move, FCC Chairman Ajit Pai said in December that by “replacing an outright ban with a robust transparency requirement and FTC-led consumer protection, we will enable these services to come into being and help seniors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Good Night&#39;s Sleep is Essential for Mental Wellbeing and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/02/17/a-good-nights-sleep-is-essential-for-mental-wellbeing-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 22:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/17/a-good-nights-sleep-is-essential-for-mental-wellbeing-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>We all know how a really bad night’s sleep feels.
We wake up with a heavy head, we are irritable, we can’t concentrate, we find it difficult to take joy in anything and the last thing we want to do is see or talk to anyone – let alone go outside.
Sound familiar right? Sounds a little bit like depression. That’s because sleep-deprivation and depression share a lot of similar characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicare Coverage for Substance Abuse</title>
      <link>/posts/medicare-coverage-for-substance-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 20:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/medicare-coverage-for-substance-abuse/</guid>
      <description>Whenever someone is struggling with an addiction and ready for help, the cost of the necessary treatment is a significant factor. In recent years this has become easier under the Obamacare legislation, because treatment of mental health and substance abuse disorders is now considered the same as any other medical treatment. This kind of parity has been welcome news to both patients and providers alike. As people get closer to their 65th birthday, they often wonder whether they will still have access to good care on Medicare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Much of These Things Might be Bad for Your Health and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/much-things-might-bad-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 23:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/much-things-might-bad-health/</guid>
      <description>Motivated by the rising costs of healthcare and a will to live longer, Americans are going above and beyond to improve their lifestyles for the better. With new diet and exercise programs, holistic approaches, and home remedies easily accessible to the average person, more individuals are inclined to make healthier decisions. Though it is paramount to adopt better habits and develop a system for remaining healthy, sometimes, people go overboard. As you may have heard before, too much of anything can be bad for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nationwide Health Training Debuts ACLS, BLS, and PALS Certification Courses</title>
      <link>/posts/nationwide-health-training-debuts-acls-bls-and-pals-certification-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/nationwide-health-training-debuts-acls-bls-and-pals-certification-courses/</guid>
      <description>Online CPR Program Extends to Include Medical Training Classes
Seattle, Washington: Nationwide Health Training launches new ACLS, BLS, and PALS certification training courses online for health professionals in all fifty states. All three courses will introduce advanced medical training to health professionals- such as doctors, nurses, and paramedics- that care for and manage patients during cardiovascular emergencies. The (ACLS) Advanced Life Support course will teach you how to provide care during cardiovascular and respiratory emergencies and will include ACLS algorithms, team dynamics, identifying and managing different types of emergency situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Technology the Main Culprit to Children Obesity?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-technology-the-main-culprit-to-children-obesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/is-technology-the-main-culprit-to-children-obesity/</guid>
      <description>Kids with BMI or body mass index greater than 95% or at the same level of their age fellows are said obese. The weight status is determined by a tool known as BMI. With the help of body height and weight the BMI of a person is calculated. The gender and age determine the BMI percentile of a kid. There are many causes of childhood obesity. Obesity these days is considered a serious health issue for kids and adults as it is related to various cardio vascular diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Features That Patients Want From a Medical Website</title>
      <link>/2018/02/07/3-features-that-patients-want-from-a-medical-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 23:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/07/3-features-that-patients-want-from-a-medical-website/</guid>
      <description>The way your website looks makes a lasting first impression. It creates a digital handshake – that initial introduction and “hello” to your patients. Working with our proprietary four-step process, at iHealthSpot, we launch new medical website designs that search engines love and look good no matter what device you are using to look at it; whether it be a laptop, tablet or smartphone. Moreover, we design your site with your viewers in mind, making it easy to navigate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upsides and Downsides of Taking Prescription Drugs for Anxiety, Tips, and some Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/upsides-downsides-taking-prescription-drugs-anxiety-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/upsides-downsides-taking-prescription-drugs-anxiety-tips/</guid>
      <description>Inside an anxious mind:
Voice 1: You have the big day of exam coming Voice 2: I must do well. Voice 1: Well, you hardly know anything. You are going to fail. Voice 2: Oh my God! If I fail, what would happen to my career? What would Mom say? Voice 1: Well, just face it, Natalie. You will lose it all. Everyone would spit on your face. Voice 2: I can’t fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Pitfalls of Addiction Recovery, How To Overcome Them, and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/top-3-pitfalls-of-addiction-recovery-how-to-overcome-them-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/top-3-pitfalls-of-addiction-recovery-how-to-overcome-them-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Addiction is genuine plus, it&amp;rsquo;s not attractive. You&amp;rsquo;ve likely known about the many individuals who have attempted to beat their addiction and failed. Regardless of how solid you think you will be, you could be categorized as one of the regular pitfalls that numerous others do. Actually, conquering addiction will be one of the hardest things you&amp;rsquo;ve needed to confront up to this point. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to see several basic difficulties to turning into an example of overcoming adversity with the goal that you can figure out how to defeat them in order that they happen to influence your recovery procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Professionals Must Have Positive Online Reputations</title>
      <link>/posts/medical-professionals-must-have-positive-online-reputations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 18:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/medical-professionals-must-have-positive-online-reputations/</guid>
      <description>Potential clients research providers before they make purchasing decisions in various fields. The medical profession isn&amp;rsquo;t any different. In fact, potential medical clients are more likely to take their research to heart when they look for care providers. Human beings have a natural mistrust of unknown medical professionals as well as medical professionals that have negative aspects. That&amp;rsquo;s why online reputation is everything. Your practice will only get one opportunity to entice a prospective client to obtain your services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment for Heroin Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>There is a major crisis affecting the health and welfare of many Americans today, and this threat to the state of America’s health isn’t a virus. The threat is the epidemic of heroin use that is affecting people at every level of society in the United States. The current heroin epidemic is larger and more broad-ranging than any addiction crisis we’ve ever seen before, which is why the crisis had gotten the attention of the government and our medical treatment system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine Has Made a Step Forward - 10 New Digital Technologies That Help Save Lives</title>
      <link>/posts/medicine-has-made-a-step-forward-10-new-digital-technologies-that-help-save-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 19:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/medicine-has-made-a-step-forward-10-new-digital-technologies-that-help-save-lives/</guid>
      <description>The medical and healthcare world has been blossoming with various changes that have been happening fast. It’s actually quite unbelievable how quickly these changes have occurred. While it can be quite difficult to be able to see these changes from an outside perspective they are there. The future of healthcare is changing literally every single day, the world around health is evolving and new tech is being introduced to hospitals and care units all over the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Clinical Trial Technology Innovations to Watch For in 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/01/27/5-clinical-trial-technology-innovations-watch-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 20:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/27/5-clinical-trial-technology-innovations-watch-2018/</guid>
      <description>Clinical trial technology has come a long way from when site administrators used a touch-tone keypad on a phone to randomize patients and order drugs. But with so many new features, it’s more challenging than ever for hospital decision makers to choose the right technology for clinical trials running at their facilities. Here, we’ll share key information on what’s changing, to help with these decisions. When making purchasing decisions for the next year, be on the lookout for these helpful new features that will become increasingly essential to clinical trial technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology in Practice: Its Impact on Practitioners, Patients, and Dental Hygiene Education</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education-comments/</guid>
      <description>Technological Advancement in Oral Healthcare and Its Implications &amp;#8211; Cavity Bites - Apr 4, 2018
[…] Porter, Y. (2018). Technology in practice: Its impact on practitioners, patients, and dental hygiene education. Retrieved from https://www.healthcareguys.com/2018/01/07/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patient… […] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology in Practice: Its Impact on Practitioners, Patients, and Dental Hygiene Education</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education/</guid>
      <description>The future potential of the dental profession lies within advancements in technology. Similar to other healthcare professions, the field of dentistry evolves in line with breakthroughs in scientific understanding and technology. This constant evolution is broadening horizons, offering better dental solutions, and improving patient care. So just how does technology affect dentistry? Technology enables simplification of once-complex procedures, it provides superior and comfortable patient experiences, and it’s shaping how society interacts with the very definition of dental hygiene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All You Need to Know About The Intravenous Sedation Dentist and Some Useful Dental Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/need-know-intravenous-sedation-dentist-useful-dental-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 19:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/need-know-intravenous-sedation-dentist-useful-dental-apps/</guid>
      <description>The time of fearing a visit to the dentist&amp;rsquo;s office is gone for good. Sedation or sleep dentistry has become a dental niche, serving people who experience fear or anxiousness thinking of visiting a dental office. For many people, visiting any intravenous sleep or sedation dentist is the best option for a stress-free dental care. Sedation dentists do their job while sufferers are under the effects of quite heavy sedation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hope For Baldness and How Can Artificial Intelligence Help</title>
      <link>/2018/01/07/hope-for-baldness-and-how-can-artificial-intelligence-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 10:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/07/hope-for-baldness-and-how-can-artificial-intelligence-help/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing quite as great looking as a full head of lustrous hair. Great hair is very attractive to other people, but the reality is that many men tend to lose their hair as life goes on. Though women do lose some of their hair with age, female baldness just isn’t the issue that it is for men.
For many men, the natural process of hair loss signifies a loss of virility and a loss of feeling attractive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>