<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Addiction on News</title>
    <link>/tags/addiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Addiction on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:21:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/addiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Pitfalls of Addiction Recovery, How To Overcome Them, and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/top-3-pitfalls-of-addiction-recovery-how-to-overcome-them-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/top-3-pitfalls-of-addiction-recovery-how-to-overcome-them-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Addiction is genuine plus, it&amp;rsquo;s not attractive. You&amp;rsquo;ve likely known about the many individuals who have attempted to beat their addiction and failed. Regardless of how solid you think you will be, you could be categorized as one of the regular pitfalls that numerous others do. Actually, conquering addiction will be one of the hardest things you&amp;rsquo;ve needed to confront up to this point. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to see several basic difficulties to turning into an example of overcoming adversity with the goal that you can figure out how to defeat them in order that they happen to influence your recovery procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment for Heroin Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>There is a major crisis affecting the health and welfare of many Americans today, and this threat to the state of America’s health isn’t a virus. The threat is the epidemic of heroin use that is affecting people at every level of society in the United States. The current heroin epidemic is larger and more broad-ranging than any addiction crisis we’ve ever seen before, which is why the crisis had gotten the attention of the government and our medical treatment system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>