<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare It on News</title>
    <link>/tags/healthcare-it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare It on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 01:35:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/healthcare-it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Features of EHR Software From the Perspective of a Healthcare Worker and Current Patient | The Healthcare Guys</title>
      <link>/2018/08/31/important-features-of-ehr-software-from-the-perspective-of-a-healthcare-worker-and-current-patient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 01:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/31/important-features-of-ehr-software-from-the-perspective-of-a-healthcare-worker-and-current-patient/</guid>
      <description>Current State of Healthcare IT Health Information Technology (HIT) is huge in the healthcare industry. Times are changing and so are the ways we record patient data. Nowadays, it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to be at the doctor&amp;rsquo;s office spending at least 10 minutes going through questions you most likely have gone over and over before. Scenarios where one doctor is not enough, and you find yourself in a new place, the repetition of answering the same questions becomes tiresome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Emerging Tech Can Help Standardize Medical Reporting</title>
      <link>/posts/how-emerging-tech-can-help-standardize-medical-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 22:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-emerging-tech-can-help-standardize-medical-reporting/</guid>
      <description>Medical reporting is an integral part of the medical industry, but a lack of standardized reporting techniques makes the field more complicated than it needs to be. In addition to making it more difficult to care for patients, this has caused the healthcare field to lag behind many other areas that use similar technology. Networked medical systems have their share of risks — any networked system can be susceptible to hacking if the hardware or software isn&amp;rsquo;t upgraded and secured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Health Tech Companies Need To Know Their Customers</title>
      <link>/2018/08/15/why-health-tech-companies-need-to-know-their-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 19:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/15/why-health-tech-companies-need-to-know-their-customers/</guid>
      <description>In an era jam packed with new technology and brilliant people on a mission to save lives, it’s no wonder health tech, digital health, mobile health, and telehealth companies are on the rise.
Now more than ever, physicians and medical teams have access to powerful tools that improve how they care for patients. And patients have access to technology they can use at home that can give them more treatment options and, in many cases, can even save their lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Technology is Changing the Medical and Healthcare Fields?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-technology-is-changing-the-medical-and-healthcare-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 18:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-technology-is-changing-the-medical-and-healthcare-fields/</guid>
      <description>Technology has proven to be the driving force and catalyst for innovation in a variety of different fields. One of those fields in which it has had a major impact on is the healthcare and medical fields. These fields have been around for as long as any of us can remember, but there is no denying the huge changes that technology has led to. The healthcare field in the modern day looks vastly different compared to what it used to, even only a few short decades ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Doctors Use Technology to Treat More Patients</title>
      <link>/posts/how-doctors-use-technology-to-treat-more-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 17:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-doctors-use-technology-to-treat-more-patients/</guid>
      <description>The mandated implementation of electronic health records systems - EHRs for short - has drastically changed the way doctors manage their practices. The inherent efficiencies of digitally tracking patients have led to the ability for doctors to see more patients in a given amount of time. Furthermore, it lets them forgo many of the formalities and redundancies associated with traditional medical care in exchange for a “hit the ground running” approach to patient care and outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Analytics for a Healthcare System</title>
      <link>/posts/the-importance-of-analytics-for-a-healthcare-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 01:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-importance-of-analytics-for-a-healthcare-system/</guid>
      <description>Ever increasing computational power, advances in artificial intelligence, and the lower of the cost computation (because of cloud computing service such as Azure and Amazon Web Services) has enabled healthcare systems – often laggards in quality improvement and technology adoption – to rapidly implement analytics systems. Such systems enable enterprises to analyze and model their processes, engage in meaningful quality and process improvement activities, and prepare to succeed in value and risk-based payment models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Mexico Hospital Battles Addiction with Health Information Technology Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/new-mexico-hospital-battles-addiction-with-health-information-technology-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 16:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-mexico-hospital-battles-addiction-with-health-information-technology-apps/</guid>
      <description>McKinley County, New Mexico, is the namesake of the assassinated 25 U.S. President William McKinley. Many locals, particularly those Native Americans of Navajo decent living on reservations, have also been the victim of assassination, but in character in addition to physical attacks. Three decades ago Gallup, New Mexico, which borders on the Navajo Reservation, was known as &amp;ldquo;Drunk Town, USA.&amp;rdquo; For many years Northwest New Mexico’s Gallup ranked number one nationally in the number of alcohol-related deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMS’s Proposed PI Rule Changes is a Good Start, But Does it Address Enough?</title>
      <link>/2018/05/28/cmss-proposed-pi-rule-changes-is-a-good-start-but-does-it-address-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 01:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/28/cmss-proposed-pi-rule-changes-is-a-good-start-but-does-it-address-enough/</guid>
      <description>Federal healthcare organizations such as CMS have spent billions of dollars over the years trying to bridge the gap between medical data and quality patient care with interoperability requirements and data integration, the mesh used to try and bridge the gap. Many government rules have been written to address the type of mesh needed and many EHR companies have claimed to meet these government requirements and claim the throne of the ultimate mesh maker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hordenine: Your Companion in Weight Loss and Some Weight Management Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/04/30/hordenine-your-companion-in-weight-loss-and-some-weight-management-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 22:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/30/hordenine-your-companion-in-weight-loss-and-some-weight-management-apps/</guid>
      <description>Are you someone who has never been able to reach your body weight goals? Well, you are not alone. There are millions of people who are unable to shed off those extra pounds off their body, no matter how much they try.
According to a 2017 study, published in Time, obesity now leads to more early preventable deaths in the US than smoking. This has fuelled the growth of the global weight-loss industry, including meal plans, diet pills and gym memberships, which has reached a value of $66.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from HIMSS 2018: The Need for Cloud, “Killer Apps” and Connectivity, But Are They Already Here?</title>
      <link>/posts/lessons-from-himss-2018-the-need-for-cloud-killer-apps-and-connectivity-but-are-they-already-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 22:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lessons-from-himss-2018-the-need-for-cloud-killer-apps-and-connectivity-but-are-they-already-here/</guid>
      <description>By Donald Voltz, MD, Aultman Hospital, Department of Anesthesiology, Medical Director of the Main Operating Room, Assistant Professor of Anesthesiology, Case Western Reserve University and Northeast Ohio Medical University In his HIMSS keynote address, Alphabet’s former executive chairman and now current technical advisor Eric Schmidt warned attendees that the “future of healthcare lies in the need for killer apps.” But he also cautioned that the transition to a better digitally connected health future isn&amp;rsquo;t just one killer app, but a system of apps working together in the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology to Shape Healthcare in 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-to-shape-healthcare-in-2018-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-to-shape-healthcare-in-2018-comments/</guid>
      <description>How Technology Is Revolutionizing Plastic Surgery - May 4, 2018
[…] This 200% increase compared to the year 2000 can be attributed to technological advancements. Technological innovation and advancements in healthcare have shaped the evolution of plastic surgery in the last century. Evidence suggests that a high […] How Technology Is Revolutionizing Plastic Surgery &amp;#8211; My Blog - Jun 4, 2018
[…] This 200% increase compared to the year 2000 can be attributed to technological advancements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology to Shape Healthcare in 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-to-shape-healthcare-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-to-shape-healthcare-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Technology is providing ever-smarter ways to do things, and professionals in healthcare are just as keen to find uses for it as those in industry. A catalyst for this is the demands put on the healthcare system by a growing population and rising life expectancies. To maintain standards of care and improve outcomes for patients, hospitals and medical centers need to adopt new technologies that enable them to work more efficiently and effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Technology Helping People With Dementia Live Better Lives</title>
      <link>/posts/modern-technology-helping-people-with-dementia-live-better-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 21:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/modern-technology-helping-people-with-dementia-live-better-lives/</guid>
      <description>Family members start to see the warning signs early on, but they put it to the back of their minds. Eventually, you’re not left with much of a choice. You need to take your relative to the doctor and you already know what they’re going to say. The person you care about has dementia, so over time they’ll begin to slip away. Thankfully, modern technology allows those suffering from the disease to lead a better life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare IT Trends to Watch Through 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/03/15/healthcare-it-trends-to-watch-through-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 15:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/15/healthcare-it-trends-to-watch-through-2018/</guid>
      <description>Technological innovations and developments in IT are transforming the healthcare industry at every level. From fostering better relationships between patient and caregiver, to facilitating improved and more valuable data analysis, the potential rewards offered by modern technology for all stakeholders is significant. Here are three examples of areas of technology that are changing the face of healthcare for the better.
Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Artificial intelligence, which can be defined simply as the simulation of human intelligence processes (such as learning and reasoning) by computer systems, has been disrupting other industries for several years, with tech, telecoms, and financial services leading the charge in this space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Technology the Main Culprit to Children Obesity?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-technology-the-main-culprit-to-children-obesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/is-technology-the-main-culprit-to-children-obesity/</guid>
      <description>Kids with BMI or body mass index greater than 95% or at the same level of their age fellows are said obese. The weight status is determined by a tool known as BMI. With the help of body height and weight the BMI of a person is calculated. The gender and age determine the BMI percentile of a kid. There are many causes of childhood obesity. Obesity these days is considered a serious health issue for kids and adults as it is related to various cardio vascular diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Features That Patients Want From a Medical Website</title>
      <link>/2018/02/07/3-features-that-patients-want-from-a-medical-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 23:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/07/3-features-that-patients-want-from-a-medical-website/</guid>
      <description>The way your website looks makes a lasting first impression. It creates a digital handshake – that initial introduction and “hello” to your patients. Working with our proprietary four-step process, at iHealthSpot, we launch new medical website designs that search engines love and look good no matter what device you are using to look at it; whether it be a laptop, tablet or smartphone. Moreover, we design your site with your viewers in mind, making it easy to navigate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Pitfalls of Addiction Recovery, How To Overcome Them, and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/top-3-pitfalls-of-addiction-recovery-how-to-overcome-them-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/top-3-pitfalls-of-addiction-recovery-how-to-overcome-them-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Addiction is genuine plus, it&amp;rsquo;s not attractive. You&amp;rsquo;ve likely known about the many individuals who have attempted to beat their addiction and failed. Regardless of how solid you think you will be, you could be categorized as one of the regular pitfalls that numerous others do. Actually, conquering addiction will be one of the hardest things you&amp;rsquo;ve needed to confront up to this point. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to see several basic difficulties to turning into an example of overcoming adversity with the goal that you can figure out how to defeat them in order that they happen to influence your recovery procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment for Heroin Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>There is a major crisis affecting the health and welfare of many Americans today, and this threat to the state of America’s health isn’t a virus. The threat is the epidemic of heroin use that is affecting people at every level of society in the United States. The current heroin epidemic is larger and more broad-ranging than any addiction crisis we’ve ever seen before, which is why the crisis had gotten the attention of the government and our medical treatment system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Clinical Trial Technology Innovations to Watch For in 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/01/27/5-clinical-trial-technology-innovations-watch-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 20:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/27/5-clinical-trial-technology-innovations-watch-2018/</guid>
      <description>Clinical trial technology has come a long way from when site administrators used a touch-tone keypad on a phone to randomize patients and order drugs. But with so many new features, it’s more challenging than ever for hospital decision makers to choose the right technology for clinical trials running at their facilities. Here, we’ll share key information on what’s changing, to help with these decisions. When making purchasing decisions for the next year, be on the lookout for these helpful new features that will become increasingly essential to clinical trial technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>