<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Healthcare on News</title>
    <link>/tags/home-healthcare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Healthcare on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 02:27:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/home-healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Great Reasons to Choose Home Care for Your Loved Ones</title>
      <link>/2018/07/27/5-great-reasons-to-choose-home-care-for-your-loved-ones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 02:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/27/5-great-reasons-to-choose-home-care-for-your-loved-ones/</guid>
      <description>When the time comes for one or both of your parents to start looking for full time care, what are the options? Well, these days, home care is right up there with the best and, here in Montreal, it is certainly worth looking into. Private home care offers a myriad of services that always place the patient’s needs at the top of the tree. If you are thinking seriously about home care assistance for your loved ones, please read this article first for some valuable information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-home Care Technology: The Future of Connected Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/04/22/what-you-can-use-for-home-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 02:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/22/what-you-can-use-for-home-health-care/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, there has been a lot of controversy in the healthcare system (high cost and declining quality of care) with more patients discharged for a home health care setup.
This is a matter of concern especially since recovery in the home setting is mostly dependent on someone else for continued care. Seniors living alone, for example, face this risk, medications can be missed, or a fall could happen in between (infrequent) visits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>