<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mental Health on News</title>
    <link>/tags/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mental Health on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 14:33:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Things You May Not Know About Trichotillomania</title>
      <link>/2018/07/22/5-things-you-may-not-know-about-trichotillomania/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 14:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/22/5-things-you-may-not-know-about-trichotillomania/</guid>
      <description>For the few people out there, who know what trichotillomania is, their knowledge is limited, and they may not fully understand the condition. They know it has something to do with pulling out your hair. But they don’t know what causes it. And they don’t know that it’s an uncontrollable compulsion.
The vast majority of people, however, have no idea what trichotillomania is. This leads to misunderstanding and misconceptions about this very real condition that affects over 2% of the population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Depression Confession Group Tells The World About Mental Health</title>
      <link>/2018/07/22/a-depression-confession-group-tells-the-world-about-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/22/a-depression-confession-group-tells-the-world-about-mental-health/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest problems keeping people from seeking help for depression is the stigma attached to mental health issues. Now a group of people have gotten together for an event, The Depression Confessions, which RDNewsNow called, “a one-day consortium” that was streamed online for anyone who wanted to tune in.
An event like this felt like the perfect way to shine a light on the critical mental health issues and topics that many felt afraid to address.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>