<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dentistry on News</title>
    <link>/tags/dentistry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dentistry on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 03:09:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/dentistry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Advancements That Dentists in Arlington Virginia Can Use</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-advancements-that-dentists-in-arlington-virginia-can-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 03:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-advancements-that-dentists-in-arlington-virginia-can-use/</guid>
      <description>Technology has made lives easier for everyone. Today, there are tools, software, and applications which can help people accomplish their tasks faster and easier. Regardless if you’re working in a bank, taking care of your kids at home or attending school regularly, technology will always intervene and provide solutions so you can better fulfill your responsibility. The same is also true when it comes to dentistry. There are several technology advancements which dentists should use in order to satisfy their customers’ needs and wants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 Tips For Financing Your Dental Work</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/top-4-tips-for-financing-your-dental-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 02:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/top-4-tips-for-financing-your-dental-work/</guid>
      <description>Your teeth could use some work, but there’s no money to cover the cost. Choosing the right approach to dental financing is not as difficult as you may think. Use these four tips and it won’t take long to find a plan that’s just right for your budget.
Identify All the Plans That Your Dentist Accepts
You already know that most dentists are happy to share information about all forms of dental insurance they accept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dental Work and Tinnitus: Here’s What You Need to Know, and How Technology is Changing Dentistry</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/dental-work-and-tinnitus-heres-what-you-need-to-know-and-how-technology-is-improving-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 17:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/dental-work-and-tinnitus-heres-what-you-need-to-know-and-how-technology-is-improving-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to our teeth, there is nothing more important than taking good care of them. Unless you want a mouth full of fake teeth by the time you are 40, you need to brush, floss, rinse, and do it on a regular basis. However, there is only so much that you can do to take proper care of your teeth. Perhaps the most important part is that trip to the dentist that you take every six months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Top Benefits of Sleep Dentistry</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/4-top-benefits-of-sleep-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 16:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/4-top-benefits-of-sleep-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>If you’re nervous about visiting the dentist or having a dental procedure performed, it may be worthwhile looking into sleep dentistry. Going to sleep during a dental procedure can help make the process much less stressful, as you won’t feel physically uncomfortable. In addition, a dentist can complete dental cleaning and other procedures much faster when the patient is sedated. There are a number of sedative types that can be offered by a sleep dentist, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological Solutions in Dentistry</title>
      <link>/posts/technological-solutions-in-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 20:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technological-solutions-in-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few decades, the field of dentistry among other medical disciplines (such as plastic surgery or medical education industry) has experienced a surge of technological advancements. It has not only made the work of dentists easier but visits to the dentist have become less worrisome. The dentistry technologies aim to make a visit to the dentist comfortable and painless while your oral health problems are addressed in full. With the many technologies utilized by renowned dental clinics like Bajars &amp;amp; Bajars to offer first class services to their patients, below are some of the most popular ones: Laser Dentistry It involves the use of laser beams for treatment and speeding up the dental treatment processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Dental Digital Health Technology More Advanced Than Other Healthcare Specialties?</title>
      <link>/2018/03/29/why-is-dental-digital-health-technology-more-advanced-than-other-healthcare-specialties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 19:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/29/why-is-dental-digital-health-technology-more-advanced-than-other-healthcare-specialties/</guid>
      <description>Technology has helped achieve unimaginable feats in the field of health and medicine. Hi-tech equipment and cutting-edge techniques are helping doctors and healthcare specialists make stunning medical breakthroughs every day. While these advancements are being observed in all perspectives of healthcare, its highest benefactor seems to be the dental department.
Dentistry has developed like no other area of medicine in the last decade. If you wake up in the middle of the night with a sensitive tooth problem, the issue can be permanently resolved during the (same) day That kind of superfast prognosis and diagnosis is, however, either non-existent or extremely rare for other problematic diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Digital Dental Implants</title>
      <link>/posts/the-benefits-of-digital-dental-implants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 18:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-benefits-of-digital-dental-implants/</guid>
      <description>Dentistry has evolved a lot in the last years, one of the most performant branches of this industry being implantology. With greater access to international courses and studies, more and more dentists started specializing in different areas and offer improved services to their clients seeking for the perfect smile. Nowadays, this perfect smile can be obtained with the help of dental implants which are gradually replacing the traditional crowns. Dental implants have more benefits than other teeth restoration methods, however they are also more expensive due to the technology involved at this stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How You Can Find Cost-Effective Cosmetic Dentistry</title>
      <link>/posts/how-you-can-find-cost-effective-cosmetic-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 16:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-you-can-find-cost-effective-cosmetic-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>The revolutionary buzzword in the realm of pride is cosmetic dentistry. This is an industry of dental care which is fast gaining an enormous amount of recognition, thanks to people who are prepared to go all the way to get that billion dollar smile. This particular effort consists of treatments like smile designing, tooth veneers and in some instances, even teeth implants. For this reason, it is commonly a very costly method without a doubt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology in Practice: Its Impact on Practitioners, Patients, and Dental Hygiene Education</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education-comments/</guid>
      <description>Technological Advancement in Oral Healthcare and Its Implications &amp;#8211; Cavity Bites - Apr 4, 2018
[…] Porter, Y. (2018). Technology in practice: Its impact on practitioners, patients, and dental hygiene education. Retrieved from https://www.healthcareguys.com/2018/01/07/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patient… […] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology in Practice: Its Impact on Practitioners, Patients, and Dental Hygiene Education</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education/</guid>
      <description>The future potential of the dental profession lies within advancements in technology. Similar to other healthcare professions, the field of dentistry evolves in line with breakthroughs in scientific understanding and technology. This constant evolution is broadening horizons, offering better dental solutions, and improving patient care. So just how does technology affect dentistry? Technology enables simplification of once-complex procedures, it provides superior and comfortable patient experiences, and it’s shaping how society interacts with the very definition of dental hygiene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All You Need to Know About The Intravenous Sedation Dentist and Some Useful Dental Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/need-know-intravenous-sedation-dentist-useful-dental-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 19:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/need-know-intravenous-sedation-dentist-useful-dental-apps/</guid>
      <description>The time of fearing a visit to the dentist&amp;rsquo;s office is gone for good. Sedation or sleep dentistry has become a dental niche, serving people who experience fear or anxiousness thinking of visiting a dental office. For many people, visiting any intravenous sleep or sedation dentist is the best option for a stress-free dental care. Sedation dentists do their job while sufferers are under the effects of quite heavy sedation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>