<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patient Experience on News</title>
    <link>/categories/patient-experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patient Experience on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 03:04:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/patient-experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Tips to Amplify Your Patient Satisfaction Surveys</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/4-tips-to-amplify-your-patient-satisfaction-surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 03:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/4-tips-to-amplify-your-patient-satisfaction-surveys/</guid>
      <description>Patient satisfaction surveys are growing in popularity among healthcare organizations as the United States health system continues its transition to value-based care. A well-designed and distributed survey can help you discover hidden issues or gems in your organization’s care system. It can also provide useful insights on whether you’re meeting patient expectations. If done right, your patient satisfaction survey can be a key player in building a satisfying and cohesive experience for patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerful Ways to Beat Psychological Trauma (Including Technology)</title>
      <link>/2018/03/27/5-powerful-ways-to-beat-psychological-trauma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 21:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/27/5-powerful-ways-to-beat-psychological-trauma/</guid>
      <description>If you are like most people, then chances are you have experienced psychological trauma without knowing it. We have experienced an intense, confusing and frightening pain as a result of a horrific event. Each time we remember such event, a shock runs through our spine, and we feel that cloud of negativity loom over us.
If you have a similar experience, you should know that you are not alone. Many have had this experience, and they have overcome it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>