<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ed Treatment Information Center on News</title>
    <link>/tags/ed-treatment-information-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ed Treatment Information Center on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 18:58:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ed-treatment-information-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ED Treatment Information Center Launches Study of the Impact of Erectile Dysfunction on Men’s Partners: Interview With Robert Nicholson</title>
      <link>/2018/06/27/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners-interview-with-robert-nicholson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 18:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/27/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners-interview-with-robert-nicholson/</guid>
      <description>As part of its ongoing research efforts to assess the impact of erectile dysfunction, the ED Treatment Information Center has launched a new online survey targeting the partners of men suffering from ED. __We thus decided to interview Robert Nicholson to learn more about ED.
1. Can you tell us more about the ED Treatment Information Center? 
The Center grew out of my own experience. Two years ago, I was diagnosed with prostate cancer, and had my prostate removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ED Treatment Information Center Launches Study of the Impact of Erectile Dysfunction on Men’s Partners</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners/</guid>
      <description>Contact: Robert Nicholson
Phone: +1-408-431-0674
Email: Robert@edtreatment.info
Approximately 30 million men in the United States suffer from erectile dysfunction, but it is often not recognized as a serious medical condition.
As part of its ongoing research efforts to assess the impact of erectile dysfunction, the ED Treatment Information Center has launched a new online survey targeting the partners of men suffering from ED. The survey takes about 5 minutes to complete, and is completely anonymous.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>