<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Press Release on News</title>
    <link>/categories/press-release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Press Release on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 01:49:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/press-release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Brian Donovan of SE Healthcare Talks About the Value of The Reimbursement Effectiveness Platform to Healthcare Providers</title>
      <link>/2018/08/05/interview-brian-donovan-of-se-healthcare-talks-about-the-value-of-the-reimbursement-effectiveness-platform-to-healthcare-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 01:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/05/interview-brian-donovan-of-se-healthcare-talks-about-the-value-of-the-reimbursement-effectiveness-platform-to-healthcare-providers/</guid>
      <description>SE Healthcare has announced the official rollout of its software platform that would help practices increase revenue through enhanced reimbursement. For this exciting news, we decided to interview Brian Donovan, VP of Business Development at SE Healthcare.
 SE Healthcare has added a new component to the company’s Physician Empowerment Suite, namely, the Reimbursement Effectiveness Platform. Can you tell us more about this platform?
The Reimbursement Effectiveness Platform (RE) is a component of the Physician Empowerment Suite™ (PES).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ED Treatment Information Center Launches Study of the Impact of Erectile Dysfunction on Men’s Partners: Interview With Robert Nicholson</title>
      <link>/2018/06/27/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners-interview-with-robert-nicholson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 18:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/27/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners-interview-with-robert-nicholson/</guid>
      <description>As part of its ongoing research efforts to assess the impact of erectile dysfunction, the ED Treatment Information Center has launched a new online survey targeting the partners of men suffering from ED. __We thus decided to interview Robert Nicholson to learn more about ED.
1. Can you tell us more about the ED Treatment Information Center? 
The Center grew out of my own experience. Two years ago, I was diagnosed with prostate cancer, and had my prostate removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ED Treatment Information Center Launches Study of the Impact of Erectile Dysfunction on Men’s Partners</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners/</guid>
      <description>Contact: Robert Nicholson
Phone: +1-408-431-0674
Email: Robert@edtreatment.info
Approximately 30 million men in the United States suffer from erectile dysfunction, but it is often not recognized as a serious medical condition.
As part of its ongoing research efforts to assess the impact of erectile dysfunction, the ED Treatment Information Center has launched a new online survey targeting the partners of men suffering from ED. The survey takes about 5 minutes to complete, and is completely anonymous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Muslim Health Professionals Organize National Conference for Health Professionals</title>
      <link>/2018/03/15/american-muslim-health-professionals-organize-national-conference-for-health-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 17:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/15/american-muslim-health-professionals-organize-national-conference-for-health-professionals/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge, MA - Over 100 health professionals will convene on Saturday, March 31, 2018 in a national conference organized by American Muslim Health Professionals (AMHP) and the Cambridge Public Health Department. The objective of the conference is to foster dialogue and leverage the skills and talents of Muslim professionals from diverse sectors across AMHP’s core areas of focus: mental health; advocacy and advancing access to health care; and career and professional development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>