<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare on News</title>
    <link>/tags/healthcare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 12:39:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Family Roles in Addiction Recovery, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/the-importance-of-family-roles-in-addiction-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 12:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-importance-of-family-roles-in-addiction-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Addiction is an issue which affects the whole community. Because even if you’re not addicted to drugs, you’re affected in a way as a family member of a relative. That’s why when a member is drug addict, its effects are reflected in the whole family system, as each member tries to cope with the instability and strange behaviors. While some families may deny the reality to cope with situation, others face the situation head-on and try to understand their role in addiction recovery, hence bringing the household in complete sobriety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/posts/machine-learning-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 04:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/machine-learning-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Information that’s accessible regarding patients is increasing by the day. And we have access to a lot of this data at our fingerprints thanks to advances in technology. We should be able to draw insights from this and put data to work. The first challenge is the huge amount of data that cannot be processed by mere mortals. Machine learning when combined with data can help us make better decisions, transform healthcare, save lives and improve the quality of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral Addictions: Could You Suffer From One of These Compulsive Habits? And Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/08/21/behavioral-addictions-could-you-suffer-from-one-of-these-compulsive-habits-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 01:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/21/behavioral-addictions-could-you-suffer-from-one-of-these-compulsive-habits-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>The topic of addiction commonly draws a person’s attention to things like drugs and alcohol. Though substance abuse continues to be one of the largest forms of addiction in the nation, vodka, tequila, marijuana, heroin, and opiates (to name a few) aren’t the only things a person can indulge in compulsively. Believe it or not, people can also have addictive behaviors. They feel a strong urge or desire to engage in activities despite their negative consequences on themselves, loved ones, career, or the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AI Will Affect Ophthalmology: Will Your Ophthalmologist Be a Robotic AI?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-ai-will-affect-ophthalmology-will-your-ophthalmologist-be-a-robotic-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 22:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-ai-will-affect-ophthalmology-will-your-ophthalmologist-be-a-robotic-ai/</guid>
      <description>The use of machine learning and AI is growing at a rapid rate in the healthcare sector, being able to tackle tasks many thought wouldn’t be possible just yet. Google researchers are doing just that by teaching a AI algorithm to detect common forms of blindness, specifically diabetic retinopathy—which affects almost a third of diabetes patients, as effectively as real-life trained ophthalmologist. What is diabetic retinopathy? Diabetic retinopathy is a diabetes related complication that affects the eyes, caused by damage to the blood vessels of the light-sensitive tissue at the back of the eye (retina).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Device which is Revolutionising Treatment of Spinal Cord Injuries</title>
      <link>/posts/the-device-which-is-revolutionising-treatment-of-spinal-cord-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 19:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-device-which-is-revolutionising-treatment-of-spinal-cord-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Sustaining a spinal cord injury is undoubtedly a traumatic experience, an experience which is universally and tremendously feared. When one thinks of a spinal cord injury, often they will immediately envision an individual whose mobility is severely restricted as a result and is now dependent on a wheelchair for the remainder of their life. However, the prognosis depends on the severity of the injury. Individuals may only suffer mild symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to Check for When Joining a Health Network</title>
      <link>/2018/08/11/what-to-check-for-when-joining-a-health-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 18:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/11/what-to-check-for-when-joining-a-health-network/</guid>
      <description>Do you know what critical information to check for when joining a health network? It can be overwhelming when trying to take in a lot of information at once that will undoubtedly affect your family’s access to quality health care providers when you need those services the most.
Deductibles, Premiums and Policy Accessibility If you are healthy, you might not consider a health network important until you need medical services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient, Compelling Communication With Baby Boomers is All About Choice</title>
      <link>/2018/08/05/efficient-compelling-communication-with-baby-boomers-is-all-about-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/05/efficient-compelling-communication-with-baby-boomers-is-all-about-choice/</guid>
      <description>Professional communication, especially about sensitive financial matters, requires planning, positioning, and analysis. Those best at building positive relationships understand how both they and the person with whom they’re speaking process information. Credibility, honesty, and empathy all matter. And when one tries to compel another into action, setting expectations and customizing the approach according to the audience can raise chances of success significantly. There are many ways to make decisions about tailoring your message and delivery, but a good framework with which to start is the different communication preferences between generations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will HIMSS 18 Mourn the Passing of the Traditional Office Visit?</title>
      <link>/2018/03/13/will-himss-18-mourn-the-passing-of-the-traditional-office-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/13/will-himss-18-mourn-the-passing-of-the-traditional-office-visit/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare is evolving quickly and HIMSS 18 offers a broad range of healthcare issues to explore, but will it mourn the passing of the traditional office visit and embrace new HIT driven meet ups?
New requirements for implementing HIT systems are changing as new health IT priorities and procedures emerge. Convergence in the health care sector is accelerating the need for interoperability, not just for EHRs, but also across clinical, financial, and operational systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answered! Top 10 Snoring FAQs and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/answered-top-10-snoring-faqs-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 01:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/answered-top-10-snoring-faqs-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been woken by a snorer in the family? You would have noticed them making a harsh buzzing sound with their mouth wide open. To your annoyance, you are wide awake, and the snorer is oblivious. He has no idea he has woken you up. Ever wondered why people snore? Snoring is caused by obstructed breathing, which happens when relaxed throat tissues block the airway in the snorer’s mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Things You Need to Know About Fighting Heart Disease in 2018 and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/07/28/3-things-you-need-to-know-about-fighting-heart-disease-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 23:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/28/3-things-you-need-to-know-about-fighting-heart-disease-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Heart disease is one of the leading causes of death among the affluent populations of Western nations. As a result, it should be one of your priorities on the list of diseases you want to prevent. Just because it is common doesn’t mean you have to be a casualty too. There are plenty of ways to fight this and other chronic diseases in 2018, such as the solutions I had the chance to read at https://medtruth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor on the Brink of a Burnout? Warning Signs That You Need Help</title>
      <link>/2018/07/27/doctor-on-the-brink-of-a-burnout-warning-signs-that-you-need-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/27/doctor-on-the-brink-of-a-burnout-warning-signs-that-you-need-help/</guid>
      <description>You knew when you signed up for the job that being a doctor would be stressful. What you didn’t know was just how stressful it would be. Just a few years into your career, you’ve found yourself feeling fatigued, detached, and even depressed. Though normal on some level, given your profession, these symptoms are all red flags that you’re mentally and physically drained. Doctor burnout has become a trending topic lately, and with good reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control Your Pain Without Medication Using The Tens Machine</title>
      <link>/2018/07/26/control-your-pain-without-medication-using-the-tens-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 23:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/26/control-your-pain-without-medication-using-the-tens-machine/</guid>
      <description>The patients who are suffering from pain cannot have better news than this, that they will be no more suffering from pain. The relief from the pain of any type decreases the anxiety level of the body and sometimes it can make the person go to sleep who was having sleepless nights for days together. The patients who are suffering from periodic pain can really feel the relief from the pain with the use of TENS machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ED Treatment Information Center Launches Study of the Impact of Erectile Dysfunction on Men’s Partners: Interview With Robert Nicholson</title>
      <link>/2018/06/27/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners-interview-with-robert-nicholson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 18:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/27/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners-interview-with-robert-nicholson/</guid>
      <description>As part of its ongoing research efforts to assess the impact of erectile dysfunction, the ED Treatment Information Center has launched a new online survey targeting the partners of men suffering from ED. __We thus decided to interview Robert Nicholson to learn more about ED.
1. Can you tell us more about the ED Treatment Information Center? 
The Center grew out of my own experience. Two years ago, I was diagnosed with prostate cancer, and had my prostate removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for Your Dentist Appointment: Tips from North York Dentists</title>
      <link>/posts/prepare-for-your-dentist-appointment-tips-from-north-york-dentists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 07:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/prepare-for-your-dentist-appointment-tips-from-north-york-dentists/</guid>
      <description>For most of us, visiting the dental clinic is never much fun, especially if you are concerned about your teeth. To be honest, even when your dental clinic is a happy place, worrying about the whole event is perfectly normal. But it needn’t be. This article looks at the best way to prepare for your trip to your dentist and should help you get in a better frame of mind. Thanks to these proven tips, that next visit to your North York dental clinic will be a lot more fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look After Your Smile in 4 Easy Steps and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/look-after-your-smile-in-4-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 02:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/look-after-your-smile-in-4-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Nobody can honestly say that they enjoy those trips to the dentist, but they are part and parcel of modern life. However, that isn’t to say that we can’t do something to make them less of an issue. By looking after your teeth, you can keep them for the whole of your life and also minimise the pain and discomfort that we associate with poor dental hygiene. This short article offers 4 proven tips that will ensure that your smile stays just as beautiful as it is today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truths About KetoCaNa – Is It Really Safe To Take It?!, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/truths-about-ketocana-is-it-really-safe-to-take-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 01:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/truths-about-ketocana-is-it-really-safe-to-take-it/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, getting a good figure has become an obsession for individuals, no matter what their gender or age is. To obtain a fit and attractive body, it is seen that people go beyond their limits and try everything comes their way without knowing that some stuff can have negative impacts on the body, especially the internal organs. But the madness of losing extra kilos or pounds overpowers every other aspect of their lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbal Teas and Their Health-related Role, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/21/herbal-teas-and-their-health-related-role-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 08:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/21/herbal-teas-and-their-health-related-role-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Despite the increasing variety of drugs, you can now access for various health problems, often, certain conditions are not that easily treatable, or you might not want to deal with the side effects they come with and end up not taking them all together. While they might not provide the same effects as medicine, teas have shown their benefits on people’s health for a long time, and healthcare specialists recommend their regular consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Boost Your Skills as a Medical Professional</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-boost-your-skills-as-a-medical-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 23:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-boost-your-skills-as-a-medical-professional/</guid>
      <description>Physicians and nurses are vital for keeping our healthcare system functioning, and as a result many people rely on them every day for their healthcare needs. Becoming a medical professional requires rigorous training over a period of years too, and that’s a hallmark of quality that patients and colleagues can trust. But how do physicians and others learn about the latest advances in medical technology, for example, or the outcomes of major pieces of research?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior Authorization Services</title>
      <link>/posts/prior-authorization-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 22:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/prior-authorization-services/</guid>
      <description>Prior authorization is essential for revenue yet creates an onerous burden on physician practices. When surveyed, 86 percent of physicians said their prior authorization requirements had increased over the past year. Seventy-five percent believe that prior authorization places “high or extremely high” burdens on them and their staff. Prior authorization requirements have increased to the point where 41 percent of physicians say they spend up to 20 hours each week on those tasks alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Success in Value-based Care: 7 Stages of the Health Data Life Cycle</title>
      <link>/posts/keys-to-success-in-value-based-care-7-stages-of-the-health-data-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 20:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/keys-to-success-in-value-based-care-7-stages-of-the-health-data-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>Back in the day – the late 1960s, when social norms and the face of America was rapidly changing – a familiar public service announcement began preceding the nightly news cast. “It’s 10 p.m. Do you know where your children are?” Today, as the healthcare landscape changes rapidly with a seismic shift from the fee-for-service payment model to value-based care models, there’s a similar but new clarion call for quality healthcare: “It’s 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Lab Requisition Online</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-get-a-lab-requisition-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 17:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-get-a-lab-requisition-online/</guid>
      <description>Virtual doctor appointments allow you to seek help as long as you have a phone and an Internet connection. But what happens if you need lab work? There are ways to get a lab requisition online and have the results in hand quickly. Here is how the process works. Begin With a Virtual Physician Visit If you have a virtual consultation with your doctor and tests are needed, the process for setting up a lab requisition begins while that visit is in progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Things That Are Destroying Your Health and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/07/5-things-that-are-destroying-your-health-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 22:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/07/5-things-that-are-destroying-your-health-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Healthy nutrition is important to lead an energetic and happy life. However, most of us don’t know what incorporates a healthy diet. Lack of knowledge makes us eat foods that are unhealthy and largely contribute towards damaging our health. The main reason to opt for unhealthy foods is crave. It’s daunting to resist taste, especially when something is right before you sitting on the table. We speak of processed foods and foods that contain excessive amounts of sugars and sodium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Eating Becomes an Addiction and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/when-eating-becomes-an-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/when-eating-becomes-an-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Food is a necessity of life and growth. It is also a source of comfort, pleasure and social engagement. But for some individuals, the need to consume food is compulsive and uncontrollable. It has become as addictive to them as drugs are to substance abusers._
Food full of fat, sugar and sometimes salt, triggers chemicals in the brain that create feelings of pleasure, like dopamine, a neurotransmitter that plays a vital role in the brain’s reward system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Groundbreaking Technological Innovations that Will Help You Manage COPD and Asthma</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/4-groundbreaking-technological-innovations-that-will-help-you-manage-copd-and-asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 21:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/4-groundbreaking-technological-innovations-that-will-help-you-manage-copd-and-asthma/</guid>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) includes lung disorders such as asthma and Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary under the broad classification of Chronic Respiratory Diseases (CRD). Patients suffering from any kind of CRD have trouble breathing because of damaged air sacs or alveoli, and airways like in the case of COPD. On the other hand, difficulty in respiration because of allergens and other causes that inflame the airways is a condition called asthma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Self Monitoring Help You to Track Brain Injury Symptoms?</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/can-self-monitoring-help-you-to-track-brain-injury-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 15:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/can-self-monitoring-help-you-to-track-brain-injury-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>Brain injuries can happen, in sports, at work, if you are in an accident – it’s possible to sustain an injury to the brain if you have had a bump on the head. What many people don’t know is that brain injury symptoms can become more apparent with time. While an initial visit to a&amp;amp;e might only give you a concussion diagnosis, ongoing symptoms might be missed if a patient does not familiarise themselves with things to watch for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Straightforward Advice About Providing Your Family a Healthy Diet, Especially When Your Child has Special Needs, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/straightforward-advice-about-providing-your-family-a-healthy-diet-especially-when-your-child-has-special-needs-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 22:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/straightforward-advice-about-providing-your-family-a-healthy-diet-especially-when-your-child-has-special-needs-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, a large number of families with children live with a hectic daily schedule of activities, appointments, and commitments. This type of lifestyle ensures that not only will it be difficult to sit down as a family to a healthy homemade dinner, but that the family’s meals are likely to be comprised of a considerable amount of take-out and frozen, prepackaged meals. It&amp;rsquo;s not a great surprise that these diets are typically unhealthy and may very well adversely impact your child’s health and wellness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 20 Foods You Can Have on Keto Diet That Make It Easy</title>
      <link>/2018/05/25/title-top-20-foods-you-can-have-on-keto-diet-that-make-it-easy-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 21:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/25/title-top-20-foods-you-can-have-on-keto-diet-that-make-it-easy-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Many might ask the question, why keto diet? Well, because it is not only effective in losing weight but also enhances your mental focus and helps in combating Diabetes Type II.
You must be thinking keto diet might mean eating tasteless boring food. Well, it’s not true. Keto is a complete diet. You can eat so many foods to meet your macros. There are many types of foods and dishes you can make to hit your daily fat, protein and carbs intake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Technological Advancements Can Help Facilitate Geriatrics and Adaptive Ageing</title>
      <link>/posts/how-technological-advancements-can-help-facilitate-geriatrics-and-adaptive-ageing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 16:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-technological-advancements-can-help-facilitate-geriatrics-and-adaptive-ageing/</guid>
      <description>As the 21st century wears on, we now increasingly rely on technological advancements for the prevention, detection, and treatment of complex health issues of the elderly. As studies have shown (such as those performed by Dr. Steven Gundry of Gundry MD), the consumption of certain foods and substances such as Lectins affect our health and lends a hand to the development of diseases. Furthermore, as people age, physiological systems of the body begin to deteriorate and, which is accompanied by changes to structural and anatomical characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is a Weighted Blanket a Real Prospect for Anxiety-related Sleep Disorders? And Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/is-a-weighted-blanket-a-real-prospect-for-anxiety-related-sleep-disorders-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 23:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/is-a-weighted-blanket-a-real-prospect-for-anxiety-related-sleep-disorders-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>We talked about the alarming insomnia stats more times than we can count, and with a good reason. The increased prevalence over the past two decades has a much deeper impact on the healthcare system then one might think. It goes beyond sleep itself and affects both prevalence and occurrence of other costly health problems - anything from cardiovascular disease to neurological disorders. In the time span between 1995 and 2005, the connection was “blurry” at best, because of the other lifestyle habits affecting the numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Let Acne Hamper Your Skin Confidence and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/18/dont-let-acne-hamper-your-skin-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/18/dont-let-acne-hamper-your-skin-confidence/</guid>
      <description>In today’s hectic lifestyle, confidence is the only companion that can help a woman successfully deal with her everyday challenges and responsibilities. Confidence in a woman can come from various factors related to her personal achievements and skills. However, this same confidence can also get hampered by an unhealthy skin condition like acne.
Having blemish-free skin, on the other hand, does wonders to one’s confidence, at home and at work. This is called skin confidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips to Maximize KETO Diet Results and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/02/5-tips-to-maximize-keto-diet-results-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/02/5-tips-to-maximize-keto-diet-results-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>From weight loss, and better mental health to the prevention of some lifestyle diseases such as type II diabetes, and appetite control, the benefits that come with a perfect KETO diet are immeasurable. If you desire to live a healthy lifestyle that everyone is talking about, the nutritional value you will get from this diet is all you need – but you ought to do everything right. When most people decide to start a KETO diet, they will download recipes in their hundreds, follow them to the letter and expect results…well, amazing results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hordenine: Your Companion in Weight Loss and Some Weight Management Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/04/30/hordenine-your-companion-in-weight-loss-and-some-weight-management-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 22:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/30/hordenine-your-companion-in-weight-loss-and-some-weight-management-apps/</guid>
      <description>Are you someone who has never been able to reach your body weight goals? Well, you are not alone. There are millions of people who are unable to shed off those extra pounds off their body, no matter how much they try.
According to a 2017 study, published in Time, obesity now leads to more early preventable deaths in the US than smoking. This has fuelled the growth of the global weight-loss industry, including meal plans, diet pills and gym memberships, which has reached a value of $66.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How 3D Printing Has Transformed the Medical Sector</title>
      <link>/2018/04/28/how-3d-printing-has-transformed-the-medical-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 21:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/28/how-3d-printing-has-transformed-the-medical-sector/</guid>
      <description>3D printing has become the most sort out technology in the world currently. This has led to applications in different sectors of the economy. Due to its vast applications, 3D printing has transformed many lives in different ways. Is 3D printing applicable in the medical sector? Yes, currently the medical sector has embraced this technology in various ways. Also known as, ‘Rapid Prototyping’ 3D printing has enabled the creation of new objects similar to existing objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips to Help Teens Cope With Stress and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/04/26/tips-to-help-teens-cope-with-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 18:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/26/tips-to-help-teens-cope-with-stress/</guid>
      <description>Teens suffer high stress, and they need help to cope with it. The worst part is that they do not find many people to help them in coping with stress. This is because they are not willing to open up on this matter and get help. If you fall into this category and desperately need help, here are some tips that will help you cope with stress. 1. Get some sleep There are many things to do as a teenager and between homework, hanging out with friends and performing other activities; you need to find an excuse to get some sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Global Health Issues</title>
      <link>/2018/04/26/10-global-health-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 15:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/26/10-global-health-issues/</guid>
      <description>Humans have been battling with various communicable as well as non-communicable diseases since the ancient times.
The advancement of medical knowledge and technology has enabled the world to develop antiviral, antibiotics, vaccines and other methods to prevent and treat a large majority of these diseases.
According to the WHO report, there has been a decrease in the number of deaths due to infectious diseases like malaria and HIV as well better awareness amongst people about the risks of non-communicable diseases such as lung cancer, cardiovascular problems and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Generation Model for Addressing Crisis Behavioral Health in the ED</title>
      <link>/posts/next-generation-model-for-addressing-crisis-behavioral-health-in-the-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 23:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/next-generation-model-for-addressing-crisis-behavioral-health-in-the-ed/</guid>
      <description>Taking telepsychiatry strategies to the next level. The telemedicine revolution touches nearly every aspect of health care today. Notably, behavioral health was called out in a recent Forbes article as the sector within the industry experiencing the greatest impact. And hospital emergency departments (EDs) are taking note. In recent years, EDs have faced notable challenges meeting growing needs for mental and behavioral health services, particularly for crisis psychiatric care, amid severe professional shortages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Content Ideas for Your Blog in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/04/19/creative-content-ideas-for-your-blog-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 21:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/19/creative-content-ideas-for-your-blog-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>When writing content for your blog the first concern you should have is attracting readers! Well especially when you are writing about healthcare, this is only possible if your blog has high rankings in the search engines. Search engine optimization is essential and if you&amp;rsquo;re not listed on the first page of search results the number of people viewing your blog goes down. Modern search engine optimization is not driven by keywords but by useful content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deal with a Drug Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-deal-with-a-drug-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 17:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-deal-with-a-drug-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Drug addiction is one of the most insidious aspects of our modern society, with an increasing amount of addicted individuals. If you find yourself grappling with drug addiction, then you most likely have a tough road ahead. Here are some of the things that you should evaluate. Learn About the Drug Knowing about the drug and what it does to your body might just put you off. Your body is a finely tuned machine and adding these chemicals into it can send it into disarray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Calculate Your Compensations After a Personal Injury</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-calculate-your-compensations-after-a-personal-injury/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 18:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-calculate-your-compensations-after-a-personal-injury/</guid>
      <description>Speed, lack of attention, difficult weather conditions, drinking and driving are all precursors of accidents which often lead to personal injuries. Persons who suffer personal injuries do not only go through physical pain, but also emotional stress and the effects do not stop here. Temporary or permanent loss of employment, medical expenses, disruptions of the day-to-day activities and huge discomfort are just a few of the consequences; therefore, it is totally understandable for these persons to claim compensations after an accident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitamins and Supplements: Why Your Child May Need Them (and some useful apps)</title>
      <link>/2018/03/27/vitamins-and-supplements-why-your-child-may-need-them-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 22:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/27/vitamins-and-supplements-why-your-child-may-need-them-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Every parent wants their child to grow up to be healthy and strong. One of the most common ways to do this is to make sure that your children are getting the proper vitamins and nutrients they need through the foods and beverages you serve them. Though most parents do try to serve their children healthy meals, sometimes, diet alone isn’t enough to provide their growing bodies with the fuel they need to properly develop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerful Ways to Beat Psychological Trauma (Including Technology)</title>
      <link>/2018/03/27/5-powerful-ways-to-beat-psychological-trauma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 21:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/27/5-powerful-ways-to-beat-psychological-trauma/</guid>
      <description>If you are like most people, then chances are you have experienced psychological trauma without knowing it. We have experienced an intense, confusing and frightening pain as a result of a horrific event. Each time we remember such event, a shock runs through our spine, and we feel that cloud of negativity loom over us.
If you have a similar experience, you should know that you are not alone. Many have had this experience, and they have overcome it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Long Does It Take to Settle a Personal Injury Claim?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-long-does-it-take-to-settle-a-personal-injury-claim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 14:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-long-does-it-take-to-settle-a-personal-injury-claim/</guid>
      <description>Before getting into this article, it is very important that you understand that there are far too many variable factors at play here for the exact timeframe to be estimated accurately without even knowing the details of any particular case. These are only average approximations based on the general proceedings and they are to be taken as such. Nevertheless, the time estimations are fairly dependable under normal circumstances and they should mentally prepare you for what’s to come once you hire your injury lawyer and file your lawsuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips For Preventing Tech neck</title>
      <link>/posts/tips-for-preventing-tech-neck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 14:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tips-for-preventing-tech-neck/</guid>
      <description>Being dependent on technology, tech neck is a common issue amongst people nowadays. Most of the people spending excessive time on mobile phones, tablets, laptops, desktops and other electronic devices are faced with the issue of tech neck. The good news is that there are certain tips that can help you in preventing the issue and feel good about your neck forever. 1. Opting for a Physiotherapy session With a quick visit to a Physio, it will be easy to understand that you can feel good about your neck and give yourself an opportunity to stay relaxed while enjoying the session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Benefits of Social Media in Healthcare</title>
      <link>/2018/03/13/5-benefits-of-social-media-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/13/5-benefits-of-social-media-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Technology, media and the internet has been having a huge impact in our lives since a long time now. But the sudden rise in social media usage has brought in much better and more advanced opportunities to business, marketing and general public awareness. The popularity of social media continues to increase and demographics show that the most growing users of social media are individuals aged 45-54.
Gone are the days when healthcare could only be provided through a practitioner by seeing them face-to-face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Importance of Videos: How Healthcare Businesses Can Take Advantage</title>
      <link>/2018/03/04/growing-importance-of-videos-how-healthcare-businesses-can-take-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 22:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/04/growing-importance-of-videos-how-healthcare-businesses-can-take-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Google says that by focusing on searches and understanding users&amp;rsquo; intent behind them, you can better target your ideal audience online. According to Google, videos can achieve greater lift and brand recall during search. In fact, it can give up to a 53% lift in: landing page visits, expressions of interests (EOIs), and key performance indicators (KPIs) – generally leading to conversions.
With 77% of healthcare inquiries beginning on search engines and patients referencing at least 12 different sources of information before deciding where to get care, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial for you to be present among those 12 sources, and to provide content that is highly engaging and influential for those prospective patients to choose you as their provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for a Better Night&#39;s Sleep and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 05:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps-comments/</guid>
      <description>8 pași pentru un somn odihnitor - Ghid practic pentru a te trezi odihnit - May 2, 2018
[…] HealthcareGuys, Mayo Clinic, HelpGuide, Sleep […] 8 pași pentru un somn odihnitor | Date despre E-uri. Ai grija ce consumi! - May 1, 2018
[…] HealthcareGuys, Mayo Clinic, HelpGuide, Sleep […] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for a Better Night&#39;s Sleep and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/02/26/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 05:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/26/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to getting a better night sleep, the mattresses and pillow companies on television will fool you into thinking that those are the only things preventing you from sleeping through the night. But there are actually a lot of factors out there that affect your quality of sleep. Here are ten tips that will help you get a better night sleep, and some useful apps you can use to aid you in your sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Good Night&#39;s Sleep is Essential for Mental Wellbeing and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/02/17/a-good-nights-sleep-is-essential-for-mental-wellbeing-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 22:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/17/a-good-nights-sleep-is-essential-for-mental-wellbeing-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>We all know how a really bad night’s sleep feels.
We wake up with a heavy head, we are irritable, we can’t concentrate, we find it difficult to take joy in anything and the last thing we want to do is see or talk to anyone – let alone go outside.
Sound familiar right? Sounds a little bit like depression. That’s because sleep-deprivation and depression share a lot of similar characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Much of These Things Might be Bad for Your Health and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/much-things-might-bad-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 23:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/much-things-might-bad-health/</guid>
      <description>Motivated by the rising costs of healthcare and a will to live longer, Americans are going above and beyond to improve their lifestyles for the better. With new diet and exercise programs, holistic approaches, and home remedies easily accessible to the average person, more individuals are inclined to make healthier decisions. Though it is paramount to adopt better habits and develop a system for remaining healthy, sometimes, people go overboard. As you may have heard before, too much of anything can be bad for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Technology the Main Culprit to Children Obesity?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-technology-the-main-culprit-to-children-obesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/is-technology-the-main-culprit-to-children-obesity/</guid>
      <description>Kids with BMI or body mass index greater than 95% or at the same level of their age fellows are said obese. The weight status is determined by a tool known as BMI. With the help of body height and weight the BMI of a person is calculated. The gender and age determine the BMI percentile of a kid. There are many causes of childhood obesity. Obesity these days is considered a serious health issue for kids and adults as it is related to various cardio vascular diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upsides and Downsides of Taking Prescription Drugs for Anxiety, Tips, and some Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/upsides-downsides-taking-prescription-drugs-anxiety-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/upsides-downsides-taking-prescription-drugs-anxiety-tips/</guid>
      <description>Inside an anxious mind:
Voice 1: You have the big day of exam coming Voice 2: I must do well. Voice 1: Well, you hardly know anything. You are going to fail. Voice 2: Oh my God! If I fail, what would happen to my career? What would Mom say? Voice 1: Well, just face it, Natalie. You will lose it all. Everyone would spit on your face. Voice 2: I can’t fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Pitfalls of Addiction Recovery, How To Overcome Them, and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/top-3-pitfalls-of-addiction-recovery-how-to-overcome-them-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/top-3-pitfalls-of-addiction-recovery-how-to-overcome-them-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Addiction is genuine plus, it&amp;rsquo;s not attractive. You&amp;rsquo;ve likely known about the many individuals who have attempted to beat their addiction and failed. Regardless of how solid you think you will be, you could be categorized as one of the regular pitfalls that numerous others do. Actually, conquering addiction will be one of the hardest things you&amp;rsquo;ve needed to confront up to this point. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to see several basic difficulties to turning into an example of overcoming adversity with the goal that you can figure out how to defeat them in order that they happen to influence your recovery procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment for Heroin Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>There is a major crisis affecting the health and welfare of many Americans today, and this threat to the state of America’s health isn’t a virus. The threat is the epidemic of heroin use that is affecting people at every level of society in the United States. The current heroin epidemic is larger and more broad-ranging than any addiction crisis we’ve ever seen before, which is why the crisis had gotten the attention of the government and our medical treatment system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology in Practice: Its Impact on Practitioners, Patients, and Dental Hygiene Education</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education-comments/</guid>
      <description>Technological Advancement in Oral Healthcare and Its Implications &amp;#8211; Cavity Bites - Apr 4, 2018
[…] Porter, Y. (2018). Technology in practice: Its impact on practitioners, patients, and dental hygiene education. Retrieved from https://www.healthcareguys.com/2018/01/07/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patient… […] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology in Practice: Its Impact on Practitioners, Patients, and Dental Hygiene Education</title>
      <link>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technology-in-practice-its-impact-on-practitioners-patients-and-dental-hygiene-education/</guid>
      <description>The future potential of the dental profession lies within advancements in technology. Similar to other healthcare professions, the field of dentistry evolves in line with breakthroughs in scientific understanding and technology. This constant evolution is broadening horizons, offering better dental solutions, and improving patient care. So just how does technology affect dentistry? Technology enables simplification of once-complex procedures, it provides superior and comfortable patient experiences, and it’s shaping how society interacts with the very definition of dental hygiene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All You Need to Know About The Intravenous Sedation Dentist and Some Useful Dental Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/need-know-intravenous-sedation-dentist-useful-dental-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 19:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/need-know-intravenous-sedation-dentist-useful-dental-apps/</guid>
      <description>The time of fearing a visit to the dentist&amp;rsquo;s office is gone for good. Sedation or sleep dentistry has become a dental niche, serving people who experience fear or anxiousness thinking of visiting a dental office. For many people, visiting any intravenous sleep or sedation dentist is the best option for a stress-free dental care. Sedation dentists do their job while sufferers are under the effects of quite heavy sedation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hope For Baldness and How Can Artificial Intelligence Help</title>
      <link>/2018/01/07/hope-for-baldness-and-how-can-artificial-intelligence-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 10:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/07/hope-for-baldness-and-how-can-artificial-intelligence-help/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing quite as great looking as a full head of lustrous hair. Great hair is very attractive to other people, but the reality is that many men tend to lose their hair as life goes on. Though women do lose some of their hair with age, female baldness just isn’t the issue that it is for men.
For many men, the natural process of hair loss signifies a loss of virility and a loss of feeling attractive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>