<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mhealth Amp Apps on News</title>
    <link>/tags/mhealth-amp-apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mhealth Amp Apps on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 03:38:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mhealth-amp-apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>mHealth Applications: Brand New Way to Manage Your Healthcare Business</title>
      <link>/posts/mhealth-applications-brand-new-way-to-manage-your-healthcare-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 03:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mhealth-applications-brand-new-way-to-manage-your-healthcare-business/</guid>
      <description>No matter what task you want to complete – make an appointment to have a haircut, buy a pair of trousers or find your way around a new city – there’s probably an app for that. Healthcare industry had no other choice but try to adapt to the mobile revolution: by 2023, the global mHealth market is expected to top $ 102 billion (up from $ 28.32 billion in 2018). Why do both patients and healthcare professionals use mobile applications?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Mexico Hospital Battles Addiction with Health Information Technology Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/new-mexico-hospital-battles-addiction-with-health-information-technology-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 16:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-mexico-hospital-battles-addiction-with-health-information-technology-apps/</guid>
      <description>McKinley County, New Mexico, is the namesake of the assassinated 25 U.S. President William McKinley. Many locals, particularly those Native Americans of Navajo decent living on reservations, have also been the victim of assassination, but in character in addition to physical attacks. Three decades ago Gallup, New Mexico, which borders on the Navajo Reservation, was known as &amp;ldquo;Drunk Town, USA.&amp;rdquo; For many years Northwest New Mexico’s Gallup ranked number one nationally in the number of alcohol-related deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deal with a Drug Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-deal-with-a-drug-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 17:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-deal-with-a-drug-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Drug addiction is one of the most insidious aspects of our modern society, with an increasing amount of addicted individuals. If you find yourself grappling with drug addiction, then you most likely have a tough road ahead. Here are some of the things that you should evaluate. Learn About the Drug Knowing about the drug and what it does to your body might just put you off. Your body is a finely tuned machine and adding these chemicals into it can send it into disarray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for a Better Night&#39;s Sleep and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 05:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps-comments/</guid>
      <description>8 pași pentru un somn odihnitor - Ghid practic pentru a te trezi odihnit - May 2, 2018
[…] HealthcareGuys, Mayo Clinic, HelpGuide, Sleep […] 8 pași pentru un somn odihnitor | Date despre E-uri. Ai grija ce consumi! - May 1, 2018
[…] HealthcareGuys, Mayo Clinic, HelpGuide, Sleep […] </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>