<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Education on News</title>
    <link>/tags/medical-education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medical Education on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:33:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/medical-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Savvy Ways to Pass the MCAT</title>
      <link>/posts/tech-savvy-ways-to-pass-the-mcat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tech-savvy-ways-to-pass-the-mcat/</guid>
      <description>Prospective medical students are required to complete the Medical College Admissions Test before starting their medical program. The exam tests the student’s medical knowledge and determines if they are the best fit for the college-based program. Future doctors who hope to start their program soon should review tech-savvy options that enable them to pass the MCAT.
Online Calendars and Apps An online calendar or app is ideal for tracking the information the student covers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Boost Your Skills as a Medical Professional</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-boost-your-skills-as-a-medical-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 23:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-boost-your-skills-as-a-medical-professional/</guid>
      <description>Physicians and nurses are vital for keeping our healthcare system functioning, and as a result many people rely on them every day for their healthcare needs. Becoming a medical professional requires rigorous training over a period of years too, and that’s a hallmark of quality that patients and colleagues can trust. But how do physicians and others learn about the latest advances in medical technology, for example, or the outcomes of major pieces of research?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>