<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dentistry on News</title>
    <link>/categories/dentistry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dentistry on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 02:41:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/dentistry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 Tips For Financing Your Dental Work</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/top-4-tips-for-financing-your-dental-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 02:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/top-4-tips-for-financing-your-dental-work/</guid>
      <description>Your teeth could use some work, but there’s no money to cover the cost. Choosing the right approach to dental financing is not as difficult as you may think. Use these four tips and it won’t take long to find a plan that’s just right for your budget.
Identify All the Plans That Your Dentist Accepts
You already know that most dentists are happy to share information about all forms of dental insurance they accept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dental Work and Tinnitus: Here’s What You Need to Know, and How Technology is Changing Dentistry</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/dental-work-and-tinnitus-heres-what-you-need-to-know-and-how-technology-is-improving-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 17:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/dental-work-and-tinnitus-heres-what-you-need-to-know-and-how-technology-is-improving-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to our teeth, there is nothing more important than taking good care of them. Unless you want a mouth full of fake teeth by the time you are 40, you need to brush, floss, rinse, and do it on a regular basis. However, there is only so much that you can do to take proper care of your teeth. Perhaps the most important part is that trip to the dentist that you take every six months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Top Benefits of Sleep Dentistry</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/4-top-benefits-of-sleep-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 16:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/4-top-benefits-of-sleep-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>If you’re nervous about visiting the dentist or having a dental procedure performed, it may be worthwhile looking into sleep dentistry. Going to sleep during a dental procedure can help make the process much less stressful, as you won’t feel physically uncomfortable. In addition, a dentist can complete dental cleaning and other procedures much faster when the patient is sedated. There are a number of sedative types that can be offered by a sleep dentist, including:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>