<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health Apps on News</title>
    <link>/tags/health-apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health Apps on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 01:05:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/health-apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Truths About KetoCaNa – Is It Really Safe To Take It?!, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/truths-about-ketocana-is-it-really-safe-to-take-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 01:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/truths-about-ketocana-is-it-really-safe-to-take-it/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, getting a good figure has become an obsession for individuals, no matter what their gender or age is. To obtain a fit and attractive body, it is seen that people go beyond their limits and try everything comes their way without knowing that some stuff can have negative impacts on the body, especially the internal organs. But the madness of losing extra kilos or pounds overpowers every other aspect of their lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Much of These Things Might be Bad for Your Health and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/much-things-might-bad-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 23:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/much-things-might-bad-health/</guid>
      <description>Motivated by the rising costs of healthcare and a will to live longer, Americans are going above and beyond to improve their lifestyles for the better. With new diet and exercise programs, holistic approaches, and home remedies easily accessible to the average person, more individuals are inclined to make healthier decisions. Though it is paramount to adopt better habits and develop a system for remaining healthy, sometimes, people go overboard. As you may have heard before, too much of anything can be bad for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upsides and Downsides of Taking Prescription Drugs for Anxiety, Tips, and some Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/upsides-downsides-taking-prescription-drugs-anxiety-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/upsides-downsides-taking-prescription-drugs-anxiety-tips/</guid>
      <description>Inside an anxious mind:
Voice 1: You have the big day of exam coming Voice 2: I must do well. Voice 1: Well, you hardly know anything. You are going to fail. Voice 2: Oh my God! If I fail, what would happen to my career? What would Mom say? Voice 1: Well, just face it, Natalie. You will lose it all. Everyone would spit on your face. Voice 2: I can’t fail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>