<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Healthcare Guys on News</title>
    <link>/tags/the-healthcare-guys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Healthcare Guys on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 12:39:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/the-healthcare-guys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Family Roles in Addiction Recovery, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/the-importance-of-family-roles-in-addiction-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 12:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-importance-of-family-roles-in-addiction-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Addiction is an issue which affects the whole community. Because even if you’re not addicted to drugs, you’re affected in a way as a family member of a relative. That’s why when a member is drug addict, its effects are reflected in the whole family system, as each member tries to cope with the instability and strange behaviors. While some families may deny the reality to cope with situation, others face the situation head-on and try to understand their role in addiction recovery, hence bringing the household in complete sobriety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Technology is Changing the Medical and Healthcare Fields?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-technology-is-changing-the-medical-and-healthcare-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 18:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-technology-is-changing-the-medical-and-healthcare-fields/</guid>
      <description>Technology has proven to be the driving force and catalyst for innovation in a variety of different fields. One of those fields in which it has had a major impact on is the healthcare and medical fields. These fields have been around for as long as any of us can remember, but there is no denying the huge changes that technology has led to. The healthcare field in the modern day looks vastly different compared to what it used to, even only a few short decades ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Doctors Use Technology to Treat More Patients</title>
      <link>/posts/how-doctors-use-technology-to-treat-more-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 17:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-doctors-use-technology-to-treat-more-patients/</guid>
      <description>The mandated implementation of electronic health records systems - EHRs for short - has drastically changed the way doctors manage their practices. The inherent efficiencies of digitally tracking patients have led to the ability for doctors to see more patients in a given amount of time. Furthermore, it lets them forgo many of the formalities and redundancies associated with traditional medical care in exchange for a “hit the ground running” approach to patient care and outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Mobile Technology is Helping Developing Countries Gain Access to Better Healthcare</title>
      <link>/posts/how-mobile-technology-is-helping-developing-countries-gain-access-to-better-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 21:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-mobile-technology-is-helping-developing-countries-gain-access-to-better-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>The battle to bring reliable healthcare to the developing parts of the world is still very much an unfinished one. But now, thanks to modern, mobile-focused technologies, the industrializing world has new, promising tools at its disposal for addressing the coverage gap that exists between nations and sometimes between territories within nations. The Problem Being Tackled To begin with, there are two numbers to keep in mind. Rather, two ratios:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Device which is Revolutionising Treatment of Spinal Cord Injuries</title>
      <link>/posts/the-device-which-is-revolutionising-treatment-of-spinal-cord-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 19:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-device-which-is-revolutionising-treatment-of-spinal-cord-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Sustaining a spinal cord injury is undoubtedly a traumatic experience, an experience which is universally and tremendously feared. When one thinks of a spinal cord injury, often they will immediately envision an individual whose mobility is severely restricted as a result and is now dependent on a wheelchair for the remainder of their life. However, the prognosis depends on the severity of the injury. Individuals may only suffer mild symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 Tips For Financing Your Dental Work</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/top-4-tips-for-financing-your-dental-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 02:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/top-4-tips-for-financing-your-dental-work/</guid>
      <description>Your teeth could use some work, but there’s no money to cover the cost. Choosing the right approach to dental financing is not as difficult as you may think. Use these four tips and it won’t take long to find a plan that’s just right for your budget.
Identify All the Plans That Your Dentist Accepts
You already know that most dentists are happy to share information about all forms of dental insurance they accept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answered! Top 10 Snoring FAQs and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/answered-top-10-snoring-faqs-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 01:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/answered-top-10-snoring-faqs-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been woken by a snorer in the family? You would have noticed them making a harsh buzzing sound with their mouth wide open. To your annoyance, you are wide awake, and the snorer is oblivious. He has no idea he has woken you up. Ever wondered why people snore? Snoring is caused by obstructed breathing, which happens when relaxed throat tissues block the airway in the snorer’s mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Things You Need to Know About Fighting Heart Disease in 2018 and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/07/28/3-things-you-need-to-know-about-fighting-heart-disease-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 23:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/28/3-things-you-need-to-know-about-fighting-heart-disease-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Heart disease is one of the leading causes of death among the affluent populations of Western nations. As a result, it should be one of your priorities on the list of diseases you want to prevent. Just because it is common doesn’t mean you have to be a casualty too. There are plenty of ways to fight this and other chronic diseases in 2018, such as the solutions I had the chance to read at https://medtruth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look After Your Smile in 4 Easy Steps and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/look-after-your-smile-in-4-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 02:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/look-after-your-smile-in-4-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Nobody can honestly say that they enjoy those trips to the dentist, but they are part and parcel of modern life. However, that isn’t to say that we can’t do something to make them less of an issue. By looking after your teeth, you can keep them for the whole of your life and also minimise the pain and discomfort that we associate with poor dental hygiene. This short article offers 4 proven tips that will ensure that your smile stays just as beautiful as it is today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ED Treatment Information Center Launches Study of the Impact of Erectile Dysfunction on Men’s Partners</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/ed-treatment-information-center-launches-study-of-the-impact-of-erectile-dysfunction-on-mens-partners/</guid>
      <description>Contact: Robert Nicholson
Phone: +1-408-431-0674
Email: Robert@edtreatment.info
Approximately 30 million men in the United States suffer from erectile dysfunction, but it is often not recognized as a serious medical condition.
As part of its ongoing research efforts to assess the impact of erectile dysfunction, the ED Treatment Information Center has launched a new online survey targeting the partners of men suffering from ED. The survey takes about 5 minutes to complete, and is completely anonymous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Ways Technology is Changing the Fitness Industry</title>
      <link>/2018/03/17/7-ways-technology-is-changing-the-fitness-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 03:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/17/7-ways-technology-is-changing-the-fitness-industry/</guid>
      <description>Technology today has touched the biggest as well the smallest facet of life. From the involvement of technical upgrade into our daily routine to the use of technology in the fields like science and medicine – the technology has changed our entire perspective towards the things and today we do not look them at the way as we did in the good old days. From mobile phones to internet to speedy cars – technology is anywhere and everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truths About KetoCaNa – Is It Really Safe To Take It?!, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/24/truths-about-ketocana-is-it-really-safe-to-take-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 01:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/24/truths-about-ketocana-is-it-really-safe-to-take-it/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, getting a good figure has become an obsession for individuals, no matter what their gender or age is. To obtain a fit and attractive body, it is seen that people go beyond their limits and try everything comes their way without knowing that some stuff can have negative impacts on the body, especially the internal organs. But the madness of losing extra kilos or pounds overpowers every other aspect of their lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbal Teas and Their Health-related Role, and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/06/21/herbal-teas-and-their-health-related-role-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 08:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/21/herbal-teas-and-their-health-related-role-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Despite the increasing variety of drugs, you can now access for various health problems, often, certain conditions are not that easily treatable, or you might not want to deal with the side effects they come with and end up not taking them all together. While they might not provide the same effects as medicine, teas have shown their benefits on people’s health for a long time, and healthcare specialists recommend their regular consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Software Platform Helps Practices Increase Revenue Through Enhanced Reimbursement</title>
      <link>/posts/new-software-platform-helps-practices-increase-revenue-through-enhanced-reimbursement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 22:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-software-platform-helps-practices-increase-revenue-through-enhanced-reimbursement/</guid>
      <description>CHARLESTON, SC, June 4, 2018 – SE Healthcare is excited to announce the official rollout of the Reimbursement Effectiveness Platform, the newest component of the company’s Physician Empowerment Suite, created for 26 individual specialties. SE is a healthcare technology company offering solutions to healthcare organizations through data analytics tools designed to improve safety, quality, reputation, risk mitigation, and reimbursement. The Physician Empowerment Suite (PES) is comprised of three additional components: The Patient Experience Platform, which helps healthcare providers foster a patient-centric environment and enhance reputation; The Clinical Effectiveness Platform, which assesses a provider’s clinical performance and areas of potential risks; and The Performance Improvement Tools, a set of just-in-time learning modules with educational tools and videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dr. Mark Mckenna Went from Natural Disaster to OVME Launch</title>
      <link>/posts/how-dr-mark-mckenna-went-from-natural-disaster-to-ovme-launch-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-dr-mark-mckenna-went-from-natural-disaster-to-ovme-launch-comments/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Mark McKenna: Looking at the Future of the Good Doctor’s Motivation &amp;#8211; Show Girls Music - Jul 6, 2018
[…] he is also greeted by an enormous amount of support from his family. This is a cornerstone of any successful businessman, balance. His work in medical aesthetics is nowhere near done so it will be interesting to see […] Dr. Mark McKenna: Changing the Way That People Experience Medicine &amp;#8211; Jae Ink Speaks - Jul 6, 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dr. Mark Mckenna Went from Natural Disaster to OVME Launch</title>
      <link>/posts/how-dr-mark-mckenna-went-from-natural-disaster-to-ovme-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-dr-mark-mckenna-went-from-natural-disaster-to-ovme-launch/</guid>
      <description>It’s difficult to be a successful entrepreneur. Most people will never manage to add that to their list of achievements. But it’s even more difficult to be a successful entrepreneur in the face of disaster. Still, that’s the record of Dr. Mark McKenna. Whenever he has been faced with potential failure – whenever disaster has stood in his way – he has managed to pick himself up. Not only that, but he has excelled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dental Work and Tinnitus: Here’s What You Need to Know, and How Technology is Changing Dentistry</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/dental-work-and-tinnitus-heres-what-you-need-to-know-and-how-technology-is-improving-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 17:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/dental-work-and-tinnitus-heres-what-you-need-to-know-and-how-technology-is-improving-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to our teeth, there is nothing more important than taking good care of them. Unless you want a mouth full of fake teeth by the time you are 40, you need to brush, floss, rinse, and do it on a regular basis. However, there is only so much that you can do to take proper care of your teeth. Perhaps the most important part is that trip to the dentist that you take every six months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Eating Becomes an Addiction and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/when-eating-becomes-an-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/when-eating-becomes-an-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Food is a necessity of life and growth. It is also a source of comfort, pleasure and social engagement. But for some individuals, the need to consume food is compulsive and uncontrollable. It has become as addictive to them as drugs are to substance abusers._
Food full of fat, sugar and sometimes salt, triggers chemicals in the brain that create feelings of pleasure, like dopamine, a neurotransmitter that plays a vital role in the brain’s reward system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Activity in Assisted Living and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/the-importance-of-activity-in-assisted-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 08:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-importance-of-activity-in-assisted-living/</guid>
      <description>If you’re trying to choose an appropriate assisted living facility for yourself or an aging loved one, there are so many things to consider that it seems futile to read another article making recommendations about what you should look for in a center. However, today our team is here to help you consider how the majority of recommendations for having a fulfilling, happy stay in the assisted living center of your choice circle back to one thing: the level of appropriate physical activity offered to residents on a regular basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defective Medical Devices and How You Can File for a Lawsuit</title>
      <link>/2018/05/31/defective-medical-devices-and-how-you-can-file-for-a-lawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 05:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/31/defective-medical-devices-and-how-you-can-file-for-a-lawsuit/</guid>
      <description>Breast implants may not only provide you with a good-looking figure; it can also lead you to file a defective product lawsuit against the person who implanted them in your breasts.
If you have had this problem after undergoing breast implant surgery and the implants its about time you act on the issue.
Implants, just like any other medical devices inserted into your body can create some side effects. Issues that may arise may not be defined at the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Groundbreaking Technological Innovations that Will Help You Manage COPD and Asthma</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/4-groundbreaking-technological-innovations-that-will-help-you-manage-copd-and-asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 21:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/4-groundbreaking-technological-innovations-that-will-help-you-manage-copd-and-asthma/</guid>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) includes lung disorders such as asthma and Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary under the broad classification of Chronic Respiratory Diseases (CRD). Patients suffering from any kind of CRD have trouble breathing because of damaged air sacs or alveoli, and airways like in the case of COPD. On the other hand, difficulty in respiration because of allergens and other causes that inflame the airways is a condition called asthma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 20 Foods You Can Have on Keto Diet That Make It Easy</title>
      <link>/2018/05/25/title-top-20-foods-you-can-have-on-keto-diet-that-make-it-easy-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 21:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/25/title-top-20-foods-you-can-have-on-keto-diet-that-make-it-easy-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Many might ask the question, why keto diet? Well, because it is not only effective in losing weight but also enhances your mental focus and helps in combating Diabetes Type II.
You must be thinking keto diet might mean eating tasteless boring food. Well, it’s not true. Keto is a complete diet. You can eat so many foods to meet your macros. There are many types of foods and dishes you can make to hit your daily fat, protein and carbs intake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is a Weighted Blanket a Real Prospect for Anxiety-related Sleep Disorders? And Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/is-a-weighted-blanket-a-real-prospect-for-anxiety-related-sleep-disorders-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 23:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/is-a-weighted-blanket-a-real-prospect-for-anxiety-related-sleep-disorders-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>We talked about the alarming insomnia stats more times than we can count, and with a good reason. The increased prevalence over the past two decades has a much deeper impact on the healthcare system then one might think. It goes beyond sleep itself and affects both prevalence and occurrence of other costly health problems - anything from cardiovascular disease to neurological disorders. In the time span between 1995 and 2005, the connection was “blurry” at best, because of the other lifestyle habits affecting the numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Let Acne Hamper Your Skin Confidence and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/18/dont-let-acne-hamper-your-skin-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/18/dont-let-acne-hamper-your-skin-confidence/</guid>
      <description>In today’s hectic lifestyle, confidence is the only companion that can help a woman successfully deal with her everyday challenges and responsibilities. Confidence in a woman can come from various factors related to her personal achievements and skills. However, this same confidence can also get hampered by an unhealthy skin condition like acne.
Having blemish-free skin, on the other hand, does wonders to one’s confidence, at home and at work. This is called skin confidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deal with a Drug Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-deal-with-a-drug-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 17:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-deal-with-a-drug-addiction-and-some-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>Drug addiction is one of the most insidious aspects of our modern society, with an increasing amount of addicted individuals. If you find yourself grappling with drug addiction, then you most likely have a tough road ahead. Here are some of the things that you should evaluate. Learn About the Drug Knowing about the drug and what it does to your body might just put you off. Your body is a finely tuned machine and adding these chemicals into it can send it into disarray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getsafe Launches Pioneering Health Insurance API</title>
      <link>/2018/04/16/getsafe-launches-pioneering-health-insurance-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 23:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/16/getsafe-launches-pioneering-health-insurance-api/</guid>
      <description>Heidelberg 15.03.2018 - Getsafe is now offering developers an API for integrating insurance products into third-party apps, the first to include health insurance options.
Through Getsafe’s new API, healthcare providers such as medical offices are now able to offer easily accessible health insurance products to their patients, particularly those who avoid booking much-needed appointments because of high costs. Patients now have an easy way to get instant coverage prior to booking their appointment, avoiding potentially costly surprises after their procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Calculate Your Compensations After a Personal Injury</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-calculate-your-compensations-after-a-personal-injury/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 18:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-calculate-your-compensations-after-a-personal-injury/</guid>
      <description>Speed, lack of attention, difficult weather conditions, drinking and driving are all precursors of accidents which often lead to personal injuries. Persons who suffer personal injuries do not only go through physical pain, but also emotional stress and the effects do not stop here. Temporary or permanent loss of employment, medical expenses, disruptions of the day-to-day activities and huge discomfort are just a few of the consequences; therefore, it is totally understandable for these persons to claim compensations after an accident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for a Better Night&#39;s Sleep and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 05:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps-comments/</guid>
      <description>8 pași pentru un somn odihnitor - Ghid practic pentru a te trezi odihnit - May 2, 2018
[…] HealthcareGuys, Mayo Clinic, HelpGuide, Sleep […] 8 pași pentru un somn odihnitor | Date despre E-uri. Ai grija ce consumi! - May 1, 2018
[…] HealthcareGuys, Mayo Clinic, HelpGuide, Sleep […] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for a Better Night&#39;s Sleep and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/02/26/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 05:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/26/10-tips-better-nights-sleep-useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to getting a better night sleep, the mattresses and pillow companies on television will fool you into thinking that those are the only things preventing you from sleeping through the night. But there are actually a lot of factors out there that affect your quality of sleep. Here are ten tips that will help you get a better night sleep, and some useful apps you can use to aid you in your sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to Track Marketing Performance Without Violating HIPAA? Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>/2018/02/24/want-to-track-marketing-performance-without-violating-hipaa-heres-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 03:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/24/want-to-track-marketing-performance-without-violating-hipaa-heres-how/</guid>
      <description>Tracking your online marketing performance to gain a greater understanding of ROI and ultimately optimize your efforts is essential to the success of your campaigns. But as a healthcare provider, your patients’ safety and privacy are your #1 priorities. So, you face a unique challenge: How do you track your marketing and performance efforts without violating HIPAA?
Start with Protected Health Information (PHI)
First things first: You need to find out if the technology you want to implement collects or stores PHI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Much of These Things Might be Bad for Your Health and Some Useful Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/much-things-might-bad-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 23:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/much-things-might-bad-health/</guid>
      <description>Motivated by the rising costs of healthcare and a will to live longer, Americans are going above and beyond to improve their lifestyles for the better. With new diet and exercise programs, holistic approaches, and home remedies easily accessible to the average person, more individuals are inclined to make healthier decisions. Though it is paramount to adopt better habits and develop a system for remaining healthy, sometimes, people go overboard. As you may have heard before, too much of anything can be bad for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nationwide Health Training Debuts ACLS, BLS, and PALS Certification Courses</title>
      <link>/posts/nationwide-health-training-debuts-acls-bls-and-pals-certification-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/nationwide-health-training-debuts-acls-bls-and-pals-certification-courses/</guid>
      <description>Online CPR Program Extends to Include Medical Training Classes
Seattle, Washington: Nationwide Health Training launches new ACLS, BLS, and PALS certification training courses online for health professionals in all fifty states. All three courses will introduce advanced medical training to health professionals- such as doctors, nurses, and paramedics- that care for and manage patients during cardiovascular emergencies. The (ACLS) Advanced Life Support course will teach you how to provide care during cardiovascular and respiratory emergencies and will include ACLS algorithms, team dynamics, identifying and managing different types of emergency situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upsides and Downsides of Taking Prescription Drugs for Anxiety, Tips, and some Apps</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/upsides-downsides-taking-prescription-drugs-anxiety-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 19:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/upsides-downsides-taking-prescription-drugs-anxiety-tips/</guid>
      <description>Inside an anxious mind:
Voice 1: You have the big day of exam coming Voice 2: I must do well. Voice 1: Well, you hardly know anything. You are going to fail. Voice 2: Oh my God! If I fail, what would happen to my career? What would Mom say? Voice 1: Well, just face it, Natalie. You will lose it all. Everyone would spit on your face. Voice 2: I can’t fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment for Heroin Addiction and the Role of Technology</title>
      <link>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/29/treatment-for-heroin-addiction-and-the-role-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>There is a major crisis affecting the health and welfare of many Americans today, and this threat to the state of America’s health isn’t a virus. The threat is the epidemic of heroin use that is affecting people at every level of society in the United States. The current heroin epidemic is larger and more broad-ranging than any addiction crisis we’ve ever seen before, which is why the crisis had gotten the attention of the government and our medical treatment system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All You Need to Know About The Intravenous Sedation Dentist and Some Useful Dental Apps</title>
      <link>/posts/need-know-intravenous-sedation-dentist-useful-dental-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 19:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/need-know-intravenous-sedation-dentist-useful-dental-apps/</guid>
      <description>The time of fearing a visit to the dentist&amp;rsquo;s office is gone for good. Sedation or sleep dentistry has become a dental niche, serving people who experience fear or anxiousness thinking of visiting a dental office. For many people, visiting any intravenous sleep or sedation dentist is the best option for a stress-free dental care. Sedation dentists do their job while sufferers are under the effects of quite heavy sedation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>