<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hipaa on News</title>
    <link>/categories/hipaa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hipaa on News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 22:46:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/hipaa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Have You Implemented a HIPAA Compliant Security Awareness Training Program?</title>
      <link>/2018/06/17/have-you-implemented-a-hipaa-compliant-security-awareness-training-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 22:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/17/have-you-implemented-a-hipaa-compliant-security-awareness-training-program/</guid>
      <description>All companies must take steps to prevent cyber-attacks and data breaches, but in healthcare this is especially important. Cybercriminals are targeting healthcare organizations to gain access to protected health information – Full sets of health records, especially those containing Social Security numbers and health insurance information, carry a high price on the black market.
Healthcare providers are heavily reliant on electronic data, access to which is needed for healthcare operations and to provide quality care to patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to Track Marketing Performance Without Violating HIPAA? Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>/2018/02/24/want-to-track-marketing-performance-without-violating-hipaa-heres-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 03:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/24/want-to-track-marketing-performance-without-violating-hipaa-heres-how/</guid>
      <description>Tracking your online marketing performance to gain a greater understanding of ROI and ultimately optimize your efforts is essential to the success of your campaigns. But as a healthcare provider, your patients’ safety and privacy are your #1 priorities. So, you face a unique challenge: How do you track your marketing and performance efforts without violating HIPAA?
Start with Protected Health Information (PHI)
First things first: You need to find out if the technology you want to implement collects or stores PHI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>